La la la la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦啦
La la la, la la la la la
啦啦啦，啦啦啦啦啦
Aiya starting the stream, aiya Haiti Haiti Haiti
哎呀开始直播，哎呀海地海地海地
Um, dededededededede ah
嗯，啊
Alas
唉
Hmm, what's going on?
嗯，发生什么事了？
Home didn't have a notification for your Live.
主页没有收到您的直播通知。
That shouldn't be the case
不应该出现这种情况。
Are you sure there isn't one?
你确定没有吗？
Because I had already posted about it earlier.
因为我之前已经发帖说过这件事了。
Yeah
是的
This is me
这就是我
This time it's a five-day Auto-Play Next for me.
这次我设置了五天的自动播放。
I'm going to Auto-Play Next for five days
我将开启自动播放功能，连续播放五天。
It's only the third day today
今天才第三天
Hiss, it shouldn't be, shouldn't be, shouldn't be, right?
嘶，不应该这样，不应该这样，不应该这样，对吧？
Alright
好吧
That should be that guy's problem
那应该是他自己的问题。
That should be that person's problem
那应该是那个人的问题。
If it's if it's that if it's invisible
如果……如果……如果它是隐形的
It must have been swallowed up.
它一定是被吞噬了。
Oh come on, isn't it basically 5+5?
拜托，这不就是 5+5 吗？
Who the hell can stand it
谁他妈能忍受得了？
Auto-Play Next for ten days
自动播放下一曲，持续十天
I'm done for
我完了
Don't mess with me
别惹我
really
真的
Don't you dare mess with me
你敢惹我试试！
Is it okay for me to Auto-Play Next for five days straight?
我可以连续五天自动播放下一曲吗？
My head is killing me
我头疼得要命。
My brain is farting
我的大脑在放屁
Damn
该死
Sometimes a box of Cefaclor costs 122 dollars.
有时一盒头孢克洛的价格高达 122 美元。
It's not that bad
其实没那么糟糕。
It's not that bad, there's still insurance. Hmm
没那么糟，还有保险。嗯。
Of course
当然
even though they only give you three or four tablets of that Cefuroxime
即使他们只给你三四片头孢呋辛片。
probably just three or four pills, and even then you'd have to beg and plead like crazy
可能就三四片药，而且就算这样，你也得拼命哀求才行。
good relationship
良好的关系
Usually they only give you one or two pills.
通常他们只会给你一两片药。
$122 is actually not usable
122 美元实际上无法使用
I remember it was three tablets
我记得是三片药片。
How much does two tablets cost again?
两台平板电脑一共多少钱来着？
Two cephalosporin tablets without a sound card, three yuan for a lucky bag
两片头孢菌素片，没有声卡，三元换一个福袋
I remember that after the post-tax reimbursement amount here is deducted
我记得这里是在扣除税后报销金额之后。
and then after tax it seems to be over 50 dollars
加上税之后，似乎超过了 50 美元。
Two tablets, two tablets of Cefalexin... Ah, just came back from the U.S., right?
两片，两片头孢氨苄……啊，刚从美国回来，对吧？
That's pretty good
那相当不错
Thank you for the super generous donation from the king of kings, Brother Bao
感谢万王之王包哥的慷慨捐赠。
I clicked the reservation
我点击了预订。
But Bilibili didn't push notifications for your Live broadcast, master
但是 Bilibili 没有推送您直播的通知，主播。
Normal normal normal
正常 正常 正常
So I always post it in the group chat.
所以我总是把它发到群聊里。
Let me take a look
让我看看
Hmm, song request, huh?
嗯，点歌啊？
It's Little White Cat again
又是小白猫
OK oh my
好的，我的天
Okay, which AI version is this again
好的，这又是哪个版本的 AI 来着？
Let me see
让我看看
Wait a second
稍等片刻
Someone said Americans Americans take take cephalosporin as a remedy uh
有人说美国人服用头孢菌素作为治疗方法。
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
Very few Chinese people take cephalosporin for hangovers
很少有中国人服用头孢菌素类药物来缓解宿醉。
Since Americans rarely take this antibiotic
由于美国人很少服用这种抗生素
the probability of taking cephalosporins is very low
服用头孢菌素的概率非常低
So many people actually have no idea about it
很多人对此一无所知。
Oh, many of them actually take the cefalosporin with alcohol.
哦，他们当中很多人实际上会把头孢菌素和酒精一起服用。
So quite a few people die from this every year
所以每年都有不少人死于这种疾病。
This can only be described as, um, some kind of
这只能用某种方式来形容，嗯……
This is just some kind of even more hellish joke.
这简直就是个更加可怕的玩笑。
This is similar to what
这与什么类似？
It's like you might only eat it once in a long while
感觉就像很久很久才会吃一次一样。
abalone
鲍鱼
bird's nest, shark fin, and the like
燕窝、鱼翅等等
so you're not very good at it
所以你不太擅长这个。
because you don't eat it often
因为你不常吃它
Americans also, they consume antibiotics
美国人也服用抗生素。
The frequency of antibiotic use is too low
抗生素使用频率过低
various contraindications are actually not clear
各种禁忌症实际上并不明确。
It's not like the Chinese
这跟中国人不一样
Chinese people have easy access to antibiotics.
中国人很容易获得抗生素。
still watching people get up
仍然看着人们起床
Stop playing Mini World
停止玩迷你世界
I was wondering why I've been so diligent lately
我一直在想，为什么我最近这么勤奋。
Isn't this making up for the previous seven-day ban
这难道不是为了弥补之前七天的禁令吗？
Is it making up for the seven days one by one?
这是在一天一天地弥补这七天吗？
Hey, it's just the same as Tamashii's deliberate explanation.
嘿，这跟 Tamashii 的刻意解释一模一样。
Someone asked how's the Gundam
有人问高达怎么样了
Is it a life-size limited edition?
这是真人大小的限量版吗？
Ah, let's not talk about this anymore
啊，我们还是别再谈这个了。
Do people sometimes smuggle antibiotics?
人们有时会走私抗生素吗？
There are some gangs, let me put it this way
这么说吧，有些帮派……
Some gangs are skilled in both areas and handle both at once.
有些团伙在这两方面都很擅长，能够同时处理这两件事。
on one hand, smuggling small performance enhancers
一方面，走私小型性能增强剂
small pills
小药片
the other hand smuggling something else
另一方面，走私其他东西。
the other
另一个
the other hand smuggles
另一方面走私
that that that that that that that that antibiotic
那种抗生素
Alright
好吧
both hands are strong
双手都很有力。
like this
像这样
Then let me check
那让我检查一下
Thanks for the donation from Brother Feng Zhijian Sheng Mianxu, right?
感谢冯志坚兄弟盛绵旭的捐赠，对吧？
OK, why are the citizens of New Rome so sensitive about getting vaccinated
好吧，为什么新罗马的公民对接种疫苗如此敏感？
so resistant
如此顽强
the New Roman government at Fort Detrick
新罗马政府在德特里克堡
secretly releasing viruses in places like New York and San Francisco
秘密地在纽约和旧金山等地释放病毒
conducting live human experiments ah
进行活体人体实验啊
Yeah, Americans are really inhuman.
是啊，美国人真是毫无人性。
The time span was from 1949 to 1969, right
时间跨度是从 1949 年到 1969 年，对吧？
especially in the black community
尤其是在黑人社区
Take your ex-girlfriend and senior Huang Shiming to see it
带你前女友和黄世明前辈一起去看吧。
Then tell them about this history
然后把这段历史告诉他们。
I bet they'll hug you tightly with love after watching it
我敢打赌，看完之后他们一定会热情地拥抱你。
Your ex-girlfriend would probably reconcile with you directly
你的前女友很可能会直接和你复合。
No chance of reconciliation
没有和解的可能
She couldn't care less about such things.
她对这些事毫不在意。
Let me add one more thing
我再补充一点。
The US military waged biological and chemical warfare against our People's Volunteer Army
美国军方对我们的人民志愿军发动了生物和化学战。
American pilots went to Japan for training
美国飞行员前往日本接受训练
The person who trained them was actually the main supplier from Fort Detrick.
训练他们的人实际上是德特里克堡的主要供应商。
Sheer fabrication.
纯粹的捏造。
Does it include insulin
它包含胰岛素吗？
Gangs usually don't deal with insulin.
帮派通常不会接触胰岛素。
Insulin is quite affordable with health insurance in the US.
在美国，有了医疗保险，胰岛素的价格相当实惠。
can't bear to part with
舍不得离开
can be human st
可以是人类的
Some people mention this Fort Detrick in the US
有些人提到了美国的德特里克堡。
Do you know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吗？
Dr. Runrun's illegal clinic
Runrun 医生的非法诊所
some uh
一些呃
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
Due to the overwhelming American propaganda
由于铺天盖地的美国宣传
countless run-ren individuals from various countries have migrated to the United States
无数来自不同国家的自由职业者移居到了美国。
which naturally includes some doctors, right
当然，这其中也包括一些医生，对吧。
In their own countries, they actually live quite comfortably and pampered.
在他们自己的国家，他们的生活实际上相当舒适惬意。
has never suffered much hardship
从未经历过太多苦难
rely on their medical skills to make a good living
依靠他们的医疗技能来维持生计。
Then when they came to the U.S.,
然后当他们来到美国时，
discovered that the United States does not recognize their credentials
发现美国不承认他们的证书
So what should I do?
那我该怎么办？
Either go to work
要么去上班
Otherwise, you can just become a gangster
否则，你干脆就去当黑帮分子算了。
Really
真的
This is very normal
这是很正常的。
Returning to China allows seamless entry into forensic medicine
返回中国后，即可顺利进入法医学领域。
I can't take it
我受不了了
I can't get into the government
我进不去政府部门
As an international student, I can't join the government now.
作为一名国际学生，我现在无法加入政府部门。
want to read some place
想找个地方读读书
I know
我知道
Sigh
叹
then the donuts are almost gone
那时甜甜圈就快吃完了。
He's not in Seattle either
他也不在西雅图。
Well, never mind, never mind.
算了，算了。
Whether he's in Seattle or not doesn't matter
他是否在西雅图并不重要
It doesn't matter
没关系
There's no shortage of such runaways
这类逃亡者并不少见。
there are at least 8,000 out of 10,000
至少有 8,000/10,000
Just let them die.
让他们去死吧。
He keeps whining on the internet
他一直在网上抱怨。
nor does it mean he's anything special
但这并不意味着他有什么特别之处。
Whatever
任何
Now, as for overseas students, let alone the government not wanting them
至于海外学生，更何况政府也不希望他们来。
State-owned enterprises stopped hiring them long ago
国有企业很久以前就停止雇用他们了。
Do you know how many international students actually end up working in state-owned enterprises?
你知道最终有多少国际学生在国有企业工作吗？
All international students are those moles
所有国际学生都是那些鼹鼠
30 yuan has long been an insider.
30 元一直是内部人士。
Alright
好吧
Thank you, thank you
谢谢，谢谢。
What kind of dance is this
这是什么类型的舞蹈？
Thanks to Brother Sanwu for this
感谢三武兄弟。
Let me see
让我看看
Post a few close-up shots of the J-10C to check out the craftsmanship
发布几张歼-10C 的特写照片，以便欣赏其精湛的工艺。
Let me see
让我看看
Looks pretty good.
看起来不错。
I’ll pick two out of five and post them.
我会从五个选项中选出两个发出来。
Why can't I upload the pictures?
为什么我无法上传图片？
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Isn't this here
这不是这里吗？
Ah, thank you Fengzhijie Society for the media introduction
啊，感谢丰之界学会的媒体介绍
my brother's reward
我哥哥的奖励
Recently, a large number of Japanese and Korean girls have been blending into 310
最近，大量日本和韩国女孩混入了 310 地区。
last week I saw a Spring Airlines flight at Pudong Airport
上周我在浦东机场看到了春秋航空的航班。
almost all of them were Japanese girls
她们几乎全是日本女孩
Affluent Japanese and Korean girls come to Xi'an, China for tourism and photoshoots
家境优渥的日本和韩国女孩来中国西安旅游和拍照。
poor Japanese and Korean men panting at Xian San Wu online
可怜的日本和韩国男人在网上对着仙三武喘气
frantically panting
气喘吁吁
Normal hiss
正常的嘶嘶声
Wow, is there something wrong with this picture
哇，这张照片是不是有什么问题？
Why can't I upload it?
为什么我无法上传？
Well um
嗯……
No problem
没问题
This, this, this, none of this fucking works
这，这，这，这些他妈的都没用。
Do I really have to take a screenshot for this?
我真的需要截图吗？
Wait a second, let me take a screenshot.
稍等片刻，让我截个图。
Let me see if I can change it this time.
我看看这次能不能改一下。
This time it's tricky
这次有点棘手。
Let me take a screenshot and see if I can post it this time
我截个图看看这次能不能发出去
Put it down for a while and then remove it
先放下一会儿，然后再拿走。
I guess I guess this damn picture can't be shown too often
我想，我想这该死的照片不能经常展示。
Fuck, posting too much could get me banned.
操，发太多帖子可能会被封号。
Hold on, let me put up the video
稍等，我这就把视频上传。
I want to put down this plane, the plane
我想放下这架飞机，这架飞机
It might be that the image is a bit too large.
可能是图片有点太大了。
I have to take a screenshot to post it
我需要截屏才能发布。
Otherwise it can't be placed.
否则就无法放置。
Someone really asked how to deal with a headshot body, uh
有人问如何处理头像特写，呃……
Let me see, let me see the situation first
让我先看看情况。
It also depends on who got headshot
这还取决于谁被爆头了。
It's the gang leader who got shot in the head
被爆头的是黑帮头目
or just some ordinary thugs
或者只是一些普通的暴徒
or illegal immigrants
或非法移民
you know
你知道
It's not the same, you know.
你知道，情况不一样。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思？
That's completely several different types of treatment approaches
这完全是几种不同的治疗方法。
What if it's a gang boss who gets whacked?
如果被干掉的是黑帮老大呢？
We usually handle it quite properly
我们通常都能妥善处理。
Why do we need to do the debridement?
为什么要进行清创术？
so that the gangster won't be dissatisfied
以免黑帮分子不满。
We have to try our best to repair his skull
我们必须尽全力修复他的头骨
Put in some filler or something
放些填充物之类的东西
pretend to fix it
假装修好它
At the very least, it should look like his head is intact
至少，他的头部看起来应该完好无损。
It looks more decent when buried
埋起来之后看起来更体面。
If it's an ordinary person
如果是一个普通人
It depends on how much money they spend.
这取决于他们消费了多少钱。
If it's a homeless person or an illegal immigrant
如果是无家可归者或非法移民
then just whatever
然后就随便吧
Someone is typing question marks
有人正在输入问号
Don't question it
不要质疑它
What's with the question marks
这些问号是什么意思？
Hmm, do gangs pay gangs for money?
嗯，帮派之间会互相花钱买钱吗？
The gang does pay
这伙人确实付了钱。
The gang pays for it.
这伙人为此付出了代价。
We can't handle it for free, right?
我们不可能免费处理这件事，对吧？
The gangsters, the gangsters have to pay too
黑帮分子，黑帮分子也得付出代价。
Sigh, let me do it
唉，让我来做吧。
Take a look at this everyone, let's cleanse our eyes first, right?
大家看看这个，我们先洗洗眼睛吧？
Let's take a look at the Japanese and Korean girls shared by Brother Jiansheng, right?
让我们一起来看看建生哥分享的日本和韩国女孩的照片吧？
Let me adjust the volume a bit
我稍微调一下音量。
Shanghai sisters' autumn coordination looks zip
上海姐妹花秋季搭配造型
Hey
嘿
hey ah
嘿啊
Go to Shanghai
去上海
Wait a minute up
等一下
wait a minute up ah
等一下，啊
Shanghai sisters' autumn fashion coordination record zip
上海姐妹秋季时尚搭配记录（拉链款）
Well, Shanghai does have quite a bourgeois-bohemian vibe, doesn't it?
嗯，上海确实有一种资产阶级波西米亚式的氛围，不是吗？
The perfect autumn outfit for a trip to Shanghai
去上海旅行的完美秋季穿搭
Sleepy
困
But you're the one paying the bill
但最终买单的是你。
You said you posted
你说你发帖了
Then why are we live today again?
那么，我们今天为何又活着？
Seems like I was also streaming yesterday.
我好像昨天也在直播。
Yes, it was on yesterday too
是的，昨天也有。
Broadcasting again today, uh
今天再次播出，呃
Auto-Play Next for five days, right?
自动播放下一曲五天，对吗？
Auto-Play Next for five days, okay? Mm
自动播放下一曲五天，好吗？嗯
Really, today is the third day, um
其实，今天是第三天了，嗯。
310 is the magic city
310 是魔法之城
310 is indeed the Magic City, um
310 号公路确实是魔法之城，嗯。
Ah, thank you Jin Jiang Qiu Qiu and my bro for the tips.
啊，谢谢金江秋秋和我哥的建议。
Let's coax the kitten to sleep together
我们一起哄小猫睡觉吧
Oops
糟糕
Wait, it's time to sleep.
等等，该睡觉了。
Thanks, Wind
谢谢你，风。
Thank you Fengzhi Construction
beauty day double treasure brother
美容日双宝兄弟
Big Fool Master's summary
《大傻瓜大师》总结
All about stealing Y, questioning the uselessness of aircraft carriers
一切都围绕着偷窃 Y，质疑航空母舰的无用性。
The uselessness of aircraft carrier battle groups is questioned
人们质疑航母战斗群的效用。
Oh
哦
Little Japan is puffing away like crazy
小日本正疯狂地抽着烟。
What do you think of them
你觉得他们怎么样？
Do you have any special thoughts about them?
你对他们有什么特别的看法吗？
Ah, he didn't say it, he didn't say it
啊，他没说，他没说。
And now they don't even want to talk about AI anymore
现在他们甚至都不想再谈论人工智能了。
You know what?
你知道吗？
Let me tell you guys
让我告诉你们这些家伙
Americans particularly like to talk about China
美国人尤其喜欢谈论中国。
this thing is AI
这是人工智能
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Americans have no brains
美国人没脑子。
He knows what it takes to maintain such a large scale
他知道维持如此大规模的运营需要付出什么代价。
What does AI with long-duration high-definition special effects represent?
具有长时间高清特效的人工智能代表着什么？
They don't know
他们不知道
Americans don't know about AI
美国人对人工智能知之甚少。
If it's this powerful
如果它真有这么强大
is actually more terrifying than an aircraft carrier fleet
实际上，它比航空母舰舰队更可怕。
So Japanese and Korean people don't talk much about AI
所以日本人和韩国人很少谈论人工智能。
You know what I mean
你知道我的意思
Japanese and Koreans are slightly smarter
日本人和韩国人稍微聪明一些。
You know what
你知道吗
it's just that Americans really love to say
只是美国人真的很喜欢说
many things in China are AI
中国很多事物都与人工智能有关。
Why is that
这是为什么
It's just that they indeed know
只是他们确实知道。
Are you a Japanese military expert? I think
您是日本军事专家吗？我想
and then some American AI companies, right
然后还有一些美国的 AI 公司，对吧？
beaten the stock prices down, huh
股价被打压了，是吗？
They instinctively
他们本能地
China's AI is awesome
中国的 AI 太棒了
China must be just like the Soviet Union, right?
中国肯定跟苏联很像，对吧？
through certain unique and special technologies that surpass those of the United States
通过某些超越美国的独特和特殊技术
thus enabling large-scale use of this technology
从而使这项技术能够大规模应用。
including the depiction of actions within
包括对动作的描述
you can understand it as the Hu Fu effect
你可以把它理解为胡甫效应。
And Americans actually don't know
而美国人其实并不知道。
If AI can become this powerful
如果人工智能能够发展到如此强大的程度
what it really means
它真正的含义
Uh, they just love it
呃，他们非常喜欢它。
Everything in China is AI
中国的一切都与人工智能有关
This thing in China is all AI
中国这玩意儿全是人工智能
Japanese and Koreans are slightly smarter
日本人和韩国人稍微聪明一些。
say no
拒绝
If AI is this powerful
如果人工智能真有这么强大
That's even more despairing
那更令人绝望了。
It can't be called AI
它不能被称为人工智能。
it's just so damn annoying
真是太烦人了
You know what
你知道吗
I said my skills are better than his
我说我的技能比他强。
He also let out a laugh
他也笑了起来。
no way
决不
your skills are better than his
你的技能比他强。
including other viruses
包括其他病毒
They live in their own propaganda
他们生活在自己的宣传之中。
Don't you don't think he can just not breathe on you
你难道不认为他可以对你不呼吸吗？
Then you're overthinking it
那说明你想太多了。
No way bro, absolutely no way
不可能，兄弟，绝对不可能
The era of big new moms has long been over
大码新妈妈的时代早已结束。
Let's see where he's about to go learn
让我们看看他接下来要去哪里学习。
The post from the bro
兄弟发的帖子
It's the little white cat again, huh?
又是那只小白猫啊？
Go to sleep, go to sleep. Mhm, time for bed~ sleep sleep~
睡觉吧，睡觉吧。嗯，该睡觉了~ 睡吧睡吧~
Tsk hey
啧啧
I'm really annoyed by posting this kind of video.
我很讨厌发布这种视频。
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
I post this kind of video
我发布这类视频
If I get caught by the auntie, right?
如果我被阿姨抓到怎么办？
just uh
呃
That's so annoying
真烦人
Ahh, the streamer is not that cute at all
啊，这个主播一点也不可爱。
Don't think about irrelevant nonsense, host
主持人，别想那些无关紧要的废话了。
You're saying I'm ugly and fat and ugly, right?
你是说我又丑又胖又丑，对吧？
Addictive drugs entering food in the United States is also about food
成瘾性药物进入美国食品也与食品有关。
It's already legal in many states.
在许多州，这已经是合法的了。
What will happen
将会发生什么？
It can kill people, you know
你知道，它会杀人的。
Food has been around for a long time
食物已经存在很长时间了。
can kill people
可以致人死亡
Isn't that obvious?
这不是很明显吗？
Everyone, do you know what this title means?
各位，你们知道这个标题是什么意思吗？
Is there anyone studying medicine?
有人在学医吗？
Hahahahaha uh
哈哈哈哈呃
Does anyone know what the title means?
有人知道标题是什么意思吗？
Are there any guys who study medicine or chemistry?
有没有男生学医学或化学？
Do any of you biochemistry guys know
你们这些学生物化学的知道吗？
Do you know what my title means?
你知道我的头衔是什么意思吗？
Yes, hahaha oh
是的，哈哈哈哦
Explain MTD
解释 MTD
MTD stands for Maximum Tolerated Dose, and ER capital refers to the extended-release version
MTD 代表最大耐受剂量，ER 指的是缓释剂型。
It's the maximum dose and extended release
这是最大剂量和缓释剂型
Got it?
知道了？
Alas
唉
Well, thank you Brother Jinjiang who's about to retire for the tip.
感谢即将退休的锦江兄弟提供的线索。
Seems like we've captured the group leader's true appearance for everyone to admire
看来我们已经拍到了这位组长的真实面貌，供大家欣赏。
Oh no no, hey
哦不不，嘿
The key point is not the cat, right?
关键不在于猫，对吧？
If you all have followed along,
如果你们一直关注着，
Well, we have Yeh Yeh Cola, um
嗯，我们有 Yeh Yeh 可乐，嗯
Macau has Yeh Yeh Cola
澳门有叶叶可乐
coconut cake
椰子蛋糕
coconut candy
椰子糖
coconut soft candy uh
椰子软糖
It's pretty much the same as the AM12 from 60 years ago, the female cat and
它和 60 年前的 AM12 几乎一样，雌猫和
Many products have um
许多产品都有嗯
WeChat payment received 30 yuan
微信支付收到 30 元
Thank you for the donation and song request
感谢您的捐赠和点歌。
When that day comes
当那一天到来的时候
Lao Wei, in terms of current technology
老伟，就目前的技术而言
America's idea of Chinese genetically modified super machines
美国对中国基因改造超级机器的看法
Is it possible to create super soldiers?
制造超级士兵是否可行？
Not currently
目前没有
Human flesh is still too weak
人类的血肉之躯仍然太过脆弱。
It's utterly useless that humans can't be modified.
人类无法被改造这一点完全没有用。
the more you study biology
你学习生物学越多，就越会发现这一点。
The more chemistry you study
你学的化学越多
the more you study biochemistry
你学习生物化学越多，就越会明白这一点。
The more you study medicine
你学习医学越多，就越能学到东西。
So you're saying the human body is frail, huh?
所以你的意思是说人体很脆弱，是吗？
Sigh, this makes you utterly disappointed in the human body.
唉，这真让人对人体感到无比失望。
truly extremely disappointed
非常失望
Compared to other animals, humans are quite strong.
与其他动物相比，人类的力量相当强大。
Sorry
对不起
Putting aside intelligence,
暂且不谈智力，
The genetic structure of humans has many overly unreasonable aspects.
人类的基因结构存在许多极其不合理的方面。
Humans aren't that great
人类并没有那么伟大。
This mortal flesh of humans, ugh
这凡人的血肉之躯，唉
Someone mentioned the theory of evolution
有人提到了进化论。
Then the question of evolution says 'if it works, it works'
那么进化论的观点就是“如果它有效，那就是有效”。
The problem is that many aspects of the human structure aren't just about being barely functional.
问题在于，人体结构的很多方面不仅仅是勉强能正常运转那么简单。
many are purely a farce
许多纯粹是闹剧。
Thank you Fitness Wind
感谢 Fitness Wind
media
媒体
Brother Chuan, the generous donor
慷慨的捐赠者川弟兄
Let me ask you a question
让我问你一个问题
Did you ever tell the senior male student from Highlands about the likes and dislikes of the old Chinese people?
你有没有跟高地来的那位高年级男生说过中国老人的喜好？
the Chongzhen era of the Joseon Dynasty
朝鲜王朝崇祯年间
The Joseon Dynasty lasted until 1895.
朝鲜王朝一直延续到 1895 年。
He actually didn't tell him about this
他其实并没有告诉他这件事。
He also didn't know whether it was right
他也不知道这样做是否正确。
Advancing with tank fleets and aircraft formations
以坦克舰队和飞机编队推进
Some say humans need mechanisms
有人说人类需要机制
have numerical value
具有数值
Humans lack quality
人类缺乏质量
Humans have no value
人类毫无价值
think humans have value
认为人类有价值
probably haven't studied medicine
可能没学过医学。
not studying biology
不学习生物学
The fundamental architecture of humans is simply a piece of crap.
人类的基本构造简直就是一坨屎。
Human genes have too many problems
人类基因存在太多问题。
The only mechanism humans have is intelligence
人类唯一拥有的机制就是智力。
We are, if we go by the barrel effect,
如果按照桶效应来看，我们确实是
Humans are probably the most unreasonable kind
人类或许是最不讲道理的物种。
it's just that humans only have one strong suit
只不过人类只有一项优势而已。
intelligence is particularly long
智力尤其漫长
Ah
啊
It's really about the stats
关键在于数据。
Humans only have numerical values in terms of intelligence
人类的智力只有数值衡量。
There are no measurable values in other aspects
其他方面没有可衡量的数值。
pretty weak
相当弱
Sometimes is nuclear steel weaker than Western steel
有时核钢的强度会低于西方钢铁。
Generally weaker
总体较弱
Hegang steel is not weaker than Xixin steel
鹤岗钢的强度并不弱于西鑫钢。
But damn, mammals really do have some serious problems.
但是，哺乳动物确实面临着一些严重的问题。
Sigh, someone said, someone said the class Mammalia is so weak?
唉，有人说，有人说哺乳类动物太弱了？
That's how it is
就是这样。
it's mammals
它是哺乳动物
not Mammalia
不是哺乳动物
If mammals were really that awesome
如果哺乳动物真的那么厉害的话
wouldn't have been suppressed by Western steel for so long
如果不是西方钢铁的压制，它就不会被压制这么久。
Sometimes the upper limit of nuclear brain function isn't very high
有时，脑核功能的上限并不高。
Not bad, not bad
还不错，还不错
Some say our advantage lies in heat dissipation and endurance
有人说我们的优势在于散热和耐力。
Right
正确的
Do you know why mammals have the advantages of endurance and heat dissipation?
你知道为什么哺乳动物具有耐力和散热方面的优势吗？
Brothers who were chased throughout history
历史上被追捕的兄弟
Don't think that our advantages are endurance and heat dissipation
不要以为我们的优势在于耐力和散热能力。
was for hunting prey
是用来捕猎的
That was a later adaptation
那是后来的改编版本。
In the early stages
在早期阶段
Human endurance and that bit of heat dissipation were all fucking used up on running away.
逃跑时，人的耐力和散热能力全都耗尽了。
Run away from under the feet of Xixingang, okay
快逃离西新港的脚下，好吗？
Ah, because you grow from weak to strong
啊，因为你会从弱小变得强大。
In the early stages, the prey wasn't that great, hmm
早期阶段，猎物并不那么理想，嗯。
If you were to ask what other advantages humans have
如果你问人类还有哪些其他优势，那会怎样呢？
It's just that humans can dig holes.
只不过人类会挖洞而已。
or perhaps all mammals in the Mammalia class can dig holes
或许哺乳纲的所有哺乳动物都会挖洞
it's the structure of the human hand
这是人手的结构
Many mammals have this claw structure
许多哺乳动物都具有这种爪状结构。
actually very suitable for digging
实际上非常适合挖掘
You know what
你知道吗
Our ancestors were essentially rodents.
我们的祖先本质上是啮齿动物。
Loose-packaged mice running around all day
散装老鼠整天到处乱跑
We humans, we mammals are indeed not very capable
我们人类，我们哺乳动物，确实能力有限。
Teeth are not very good either.
牙齿也不太好。
Our vision isn't great either.
我们的视力也不太好。
Hearing isn't great either
听力也不太好。
The sense of smell is also not great.
嗅觉也不太好。
just
只是
You know, in human instincts
你知道，这是人类的本能。
Even modern humans are still very afraid of things like venomous snakes and scorpions
即使是现代人，仍然非常害怕毒蛇和蝎子之类的动物。
Why is that
这是为什么
and spiders
还有蜘蛛
That is a fear deeply rooted in instinct.
那是一种根植于本能的恐惧。
Because our ancestors were actually smaller than them
因为我们的祖先实际上比他们矮小。
that baseless fear of yours
你那毫无根据的恐惧
It's not without reason.
这并非毫无道理。
because he did indeed eat our ancestors
因为他确实吃掉了我们的祖先。
Some people say, will humans still have natural predators in the future?
有人问，未来人类还会有天敌吗？
Now, you'd essentially be prey to everything in the wild anyway.
这样一来，你在野外基本上就会成为所有动物的猎物。
If you don't use modern tools
如果你不使用现代工具
Oh right, I heard, I heard that the strongest Category 17 typhoon is coming, huh? Ah, Hainan, right?
哦，对了，我听说，最强的 17 级台风要来了，是吗？啊，是海南岛，对吧？
Hainan, right?
海南，对吧？
IP address
IP 地址
The attitude of the Hainan Meteorological Bureau says it all
海南气象局的态度说明了一切
Okay, um
好的，一个
The meteorological bureau, I'll close the door first.
气象局，我先把门关上。
Nobody knows more about typhoons than me, sigh.
唉，没有人比我更了解台风了。
It's said to be extremely huge
据说它非常巨大。
Could our friends in the south share how you're feeling about this? Ah,
南方的朋友们能否分享一下你们对此的感受？啊，
People in Shenzhen say they're scared
深圳人说他们很害怕
By the way, are you guys in Shenzhen taking a break or working?
对了，你们在深圳是休息还是工作？
Can I ask a question?
我可以问个问题吗？
Shenzhen, Shenzhen, are you on break or at work right now?
深圳，深圳，你现在是在休息还是在工作？
Oh wow, thank you Feng Shijian the Sword Saint, the physically absent student, for the old song appreciation.
哇哦，感谢缺席的剑圣冯世剑对这首老歌的欣赏。
I can also imagine
我也能想象
For those far-right individuals to show this kind of UGC Anime to the young far-right members
让那些极右翼分子向年轻的极右翼成员展示这类用户原创动漫。
Then they said the catapult-launched J-35 in the wash draft is fake
然后他们又说，在洗流中弹射起飞的歼-35 是假的。
So can we understand their
那么我们能理解他们吗？
Ah, there's no need to understand them
啊，没必要了解它们。
They can think whatever they want, hey
他们爱怎么想就怎么想，对吧。
Guangzhou has historically come to a halt
广州历史上曾一度停滞不前
It's suspended, right?
它被暂停了，对吧？
Five suspensions, alright then
五次停赛，好吧。
Hainan Hainan probably has everything shut down.
海南岛可能已经全面停摆了。
I guess everything in Hainan has come to a halt.
看来海南的一切活动都停滞了。
Weren't you still holding on this afternoon?
今天下午你不是还在坚持吗？
It's just the holiday now
现在只是假期而已。
You guys are really not
你们真的不是
You guys wouldn't
你们不会的
Did you still have to work a full day in Shenzhen today, huh?
你今天还在深圳工作了一整天吗？
Ah, thank you Brother Jinshan Balloon for the donation, ha
啊，谢谢金山气球兄弟的捐赠，哈
Why bother arguing with them?
何必跟他们争论呢？
Since you've awakened, ha
既然你已经醒来，哈
root should be beaten to death
应该把根打死
Hey, okay
嘿，好的
In a moment, hmm
稍等片刻，嗯。
Ah, the truck goes down 18 consecutive bends, right?
啊，这辆卡车要连续经过 18 个弯道，对吧？
Alipay payment received for Otaku content
已收到支付宝支付的宅男内容款项
Stop it
住手
Oh ho
哦吼
Hmm, thanks
嗯，谢谢
Damn it
该死的
What the hell kind of superpower is this again
这到底是什么鬼超能力？
Conan, I'm fine. Looks like the fat on my belly saved the day. Hooray!
柯南，我没事。看来我肚子上的肥肉救了我一命。万岁！
This is fucking... Japanese people
这他妈真是……日本人
do they have some fucking mental illness
他们是不是有精神疾病？
Uh
呃
Thank you
谢谢
The truth hurts too much
真相太伤人了。
Bro, thanks for the tip. Let me check the private messages.
兄弟，谢谢你的提醒。我看看私信。
Located in Dongguan
位于东莞
preparing for the night shift
准备上夜班
Go shoot a five-second video
去拍摄一段五秒钟的视频
No, bro
不，兄弟。
Are you really working the night shift again?
你真的又要上夜班了吗？
Do we really have to work this damn shift?
我们真的非得上这该死的班吗？
Are we a public institution?
我们是公共机构吗？
Can this shift crew make up for it?
这班次的工作人员能弥补这个损失吗？
Have to work even on typhoon days
即使在台风天也必须工作
We have to work even on typhoon days.
即使是台风天我们也得工作。
so
所以
You still look for me on a typhoon day
即使在台风天，你依然在寻找我。
Alright, fine. Ouch.
好吧，行。哎哟。
Emergency response units, huh?
是应急响应小组吗？
Damn, bro, if it's a public institution
妈的，兄弟，如果是公立机构的话。
if there's a mission that the people need you to undertake
如果人民需要你执行某项任务，那就去做吧。
Well, still, thank you, bro, for continuing to hold the fort, right?
好吧，兄弟，还是要谢谢你继续坚守阵地，对吧？
If not, it's just a regular private company
否则，它就只是一家普通的私营公司。
Let's just bail.
我们还是撤退吧。
Run for your life!
快跑啊！
bro
兄弟
Ah, power grid, water network, right?
啊，是电网、供水网络，对吧？
Meteorological Bureau, hmm
气象局，嗯
no way
决不
Does Seattle sometimes have typhoons?
西雅图有时会遭遇台风吗？
There are no typhoons in Seattle.
西雅图没有台风。
There's only cold currents in Seattle, hmm
西雅图只有寒流，嗯。
only cold waves and Korean wave
只有寒流和韩流
Anyway, people die
总之，人都会死。
It's just that people die silently and unnoticed.
只是人们死得悄无声息，无人察觉。
Brothers
兄弟
It's going to get colder soon.
天气很快就要变冷了。
It's around 10 to 10-plus degrees here in Seattle right now.
现在西雅图的气温在 10 到 10 度之间。
Take a look
看看
14 degrees, 14 degrees
14 度，14 度
It's now late September, 14 degrees, uh
现在是九月下旬，气温 14 度，嗯……
The first wave of deaths
第一波死亡
Based on my experience
根据我的经验
When does the first wave of deaths roughly occur?
第一波死亡潮大约何时发生？
around mid to late October
大约在十月中下旬
around October 15th
大约在 10 月 15 日
16th to October 25th
10 月 16 日至 25 日
26th
26 日
These ten days saw the fastest drop in temperature.
这十天气温下降速度最快。
Basically, it's dropping by one or two degrees per day.
基本上，气温每天下降一到两度。
Well, of course
当然
I'm talking about the lowest temperature here
我指的是这里的最低温度。
the daily lowest temperature uh
每日最低气温
Basically, the first batch of fatalities will start appearing, hey
基本上，第一批死亡人数就会开始出现，嘿。
It's about to be the peak season for corpse supply.
尸体供应即将进入高峰期。
Brothers
兄弟
I want to tell you all
我想告诉你们一切
The good days are just around the corner.
美好的日子即将到来。
You know what?
你知道吗？
The bodies are about to come in waves.
尸体即将一波接一波地运来。
children of illegal immigrants
非法移民的子女
Those kids who didn't have enough warmth, ah ah
那些缺乏温暖的孩子，啊啊
having to go out to work late at night braving the cold wind and chill
不得不冒着寒风和寒冷，在深夜外出工作
those illegal workers ah, a cold wave comes, right
那些非法劳工啊，寒潮来了，对吧？
leading to pneumonia
导致肺炎
then triggering a high fever
然后引发高烧
just one wave could sweep them away
只需一个浪头就能将他们卷走
And then there are some homeless people
然后还有一些无家可归的人
Well, until after Christmas.
嗯，直到圣诞节之后。
Uh, the peak season lasts until February next year.
呃，旺季会持续到明年二月。
That is, starting from late October to early November
也就是说，从十月下旬到十一月初。
You can consider it from early November until the end of February next year.
您可以从 11 月初到明年 2 月底这段时间考虑此事。
early March
三月初
Uh uh, thank you brother Qiu Qiu for the big reward today
呃呃，谢谢邱邱哥今天给的大奖励！
Streamer status
主播状态
My eyes are so tired I can barely keep them open
我的眼睛好累，几乎睁不开了。
Oh come on, don't talk nonsense.
拜托，别胡说八道了。
Someone asked if Donut will die
有人问甜甜圈会不会死
It depends on how well Donut has prepared for keeping warm
这取决于甜甜圈保暖措施做得如何。
Besides, he's not even in Seattle.
此外，他甚至都不在西雅图。
Is he in California
他现在在加州吗？
California is, is, is, is, is the Sunshine State
加利福尼亚州是，是，是，是，是阳光之州
very very warm
非常非常温暖
Not in California.
加州没有这种情况。
Thanks for the final donation from Brother Engineer
感谢 Brother Engineer 的最后一笔捐款。
Does Seattle have bomb cyclones and extratropical cyclones?
西雅图会遭遇炸弹气旋和温带气旋吗？
I really don't know about these two
我真的不太了解这两个人。
but I guess there isn't
但我猜并没有。
Someone said their luggage wasn't confiscated by the police.
有人说他们的行李没有被警察没收。
Then he might not be able to hold on
那样的话，他可能就坚持不下去了。
Then he probably can't hold on
那他可能坚持不下去了。
Some say the latitude in Europe and America isn't that high
有人说欧洲和美洲的纬度并不算高。
Why is it so stable
为什么它如此稳定
It's not cold.
不冷。
only around zero degrees
仅在零度附近
It's just that they're homeless.
只不过他们是无家可归的人。
It's just that the living conditions for these brothers are tough.
只是这两兄弟的生活条件很艰苦。
Around zero degrees is enough to kill you
零度左右的气温足以致命。
It's just that during the day it might be a bit nice
只是白天可能会有点冷。
It's about Xi'an, Xi'an... Seattle's winter
是关于西安，西安……西雅图的冬天
What does it mean
这是什么意思
3 to 4 degrees in the morning
早晨气温 3 到 4 度
five or six degrees at noon
中午时分气温五六度。
minus one or two degrees at night
夜间气温零下 1 到 2 度
This temperature difference is enough to freeze someone to death.
这种温差足以将人冻死。
People can freeze to death without extremely low temperatures
即使没有极低的温度，人们也可能被冻死。
as long as your core temperature drops
只要你的核心体温下降
just a little longer
再过一会儿就好了
you will die
你会死
Don't get it wrong
别搞错了
It doesn't take very low temperatures to freeze someone to death
温度不需要很低就能把人冻死。
Alright
好吧
This is something everyone should understand.
这是每个人都应该明白的事情。
You don't actually need extremely low temperatures to freeze someone to death, you know.
其实，要把人冻死，并不需要极低的温度。
Thanks to Brother Fengzhijiansheng, the medical student, for the tip!
感谢医学生冯志建生兄弟提供的信息！
watch video
观看视频
Wait a second
稍等片刻
take a look
看看
Actually, it's a common misconception
实际上，这是一种常见的误解。
When the cold wave hits
寒潮来袭时
many people will die
许多人将会死亡
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思？
It's very easy
这很容易
Brother Amo
阿莫兄弟
You just got off work, right?
你刚下班吧？
Let me see the video
让我看看视频
Haha
哈哈
window assistant
窗口助理
cute you
你真可爱
fishing
钓鱼
sometimes dealing with corpses every day
有时每天都要处理尸体
Is there any haunting Me
我是否被什么困扰着？
Are you talking about ghosts and spirits?
你指的是鬼魂和幽灵吗？
They usually don't haunt me
它们通常不会缠着我。
Ouch
哎哟
Hmph
哼
Okay
好的
Someone said someone asked what to do if there are unclean things
有人说有人问，如果有不洁之物该怎么办。
Unclean things can generally be exorcised, right?
不洁之物通常都可以被驱除，对吗？
just perform an exorcism
只需进行驱魔仪式即可
or chant incantations
或者念诵咒语
I can chant the Xin Ding and the Prajna Paramita Heart Sutra.
我会念诵《心经》和《般若波罗蜜多心经》。
I'm not afraid of this
我不怕这个
And I help them clean up the mess, alright?
我会帮他们收拾残局，好吗？
Why would he pester Me
他为什么要纠缠我？
Ah, let me show you some pictures
啊，让我给你看一些图片。
Um, ah
嗯，啊
It's also related to aircraft carriers.
它还与航空母舰有关。
Japan is having another meltdown
日本又一次陷入崩溃。
in their impression, in their instinct
在他们的印象中，在他们的本能中
The one who should be threatening them should be the Soviets, right?
真正应该威胁他们的应该是苏联人，对吧？
How the hell are you Chinese threatening me now?
你们中国人现在到底是怎么威胁我的？
This just completely shattered their defenses.
这彻底击溃了他们的防线。
Damn, that really broke me
该死，这真的让我崩溃了。
Brothers, holy shit
兄弟们，我的天哪
Well, thank you, bro, for the tip.
谢谢兄弟的建议。
Seattle is near the sea and has a rainy climate.
西雅图临近大海，气候多雨。
The temperature may not necessarily be low
温度未必会很低。
but the apparent temperature feels colder in winter
但冬季体感温度会感觉更冷。
not the feels-like temperature
不是体感温度
It's actually lower
实际上更低
sleet oh
雨夹雪哦
Bro, the rain falling on the snow lands on you
兄弟，雨水落在雪上，也落在你身上了。
It's actually rain
实际上是在下雨。
It seeps into your clothes
它会渗入你的衣服。
You need to generate a significant amount of heat internally to dry it out
你需要内部产生大量的热量才能将其烘干。
ensure your core temperature does not drop
确保你的核心体温不会下降
Your body temperature will drop very quickly.
你的体温会迅速下降。
The rain lasts a bit longer
雨下得更久一些。
Your protection on the streets is a bit lacking
你在街上的安全保障有点不足。
You could die very easily.
你很容易就会丧命。
It's very easy to die
死亡很容易发生
This is a Japanese person, right?
这是日本人，对吧？
is a meltdown
崩溃了
Ah
啊
What's there to get so upset about
有什么好生气的？
You Japanese folks will have plenty more moments to lose your cool in the future, won't you?
日本人以后还有很多机会发脾气，对吧？
That's all it takes to break you
这就足以击垮你。
Then I really don't know how you'll manage to live in the future
那我真不知道你以后该怎么活下去了。
I'm so angry I could die
我气得要死。
Some say when the air is humid
有人说，当空气潮湿时
the water molecule content is very high
水分子含量非常高
It loses its thermal insulation effect.
它失去了隔热效果。
Don't you ever think that coastal cities can't freeze people to death.
你难道以为沿海城市不会把人冻死吗？
wishful thinking
妄想
right
正确的
If you want water to evaporate
如果你想让水蒸发
liquid to gas
液化成气
It needs to absorb heat
它需要吸收热量
absorb a large amount of heat
吸收大量热量
These raindrops cling to your body
这些雨滴附着在你的身上。
It absorbs the heat from your body
它会吸收你身体的热量
after evaporation
蒸发后
That could kill you, right?
那可能会要了你的命，对吧？
You don't even have a warm house
你连个暖和的房子都没有。
and no heating
没有暖气
The food is not good either
食物也不好吃。
Right
正确的
freezing rain and snow in low temperatures
低温下有冻雨和雪
Probably very few people can understand
可能很少有人能理解
Probably only the brothers from Northeast China can fully understand.
或许只有来自中国东北的兄弟们才能完全理解。
Southerners can't understand
南方人无法理解
Just just came back from the typhoon scene
刚从台风现场回来
It's too hard to bear
太难承受了
bro
兄弟
Difficult, difficult, so many baffling things
难啊，难啊，太多令人费解的事情了。
Oh my god
我的天啊
This wind, this time the wind is really terrifying
这次的风，这次的风真是太可怕了。
Holy shit we just used all kinds of
我的天啊，我们刚才用了各种各样的
We used wire to tie up all the windows again.
我们用铁丝把所有的窗户都重新绑了起来。
Hmm
唔
Alright
好吧
Let's take a look at some Eastern European badass moves from certain countries.
让我们一起来看看东欧某些国家的精彩绝伦的招式。
Next up are a few Eastern European stunts, right?
接下来是一些东欧特技表演，对吧？
Ukraine is donating construction vehicles, right?
乌克兰正在捐赠工程车辆，对吗？
help Poland violently dismantle the China-Europe railway
帮助波兰暴力拆除中欧铁路
Well, it's just that countries like Poland
嗯，只是像波兰这样的国家……
He totally deserves it
他完全配得上这份荣誉。
You know what
你知道吗
It's really, oh my god
真是，我的天哪
It's just that he chose to dismantle the China-Europe railway at this critical moment
只是他偏偏选择在这个关键时刻拆除中欧铁路。
Old A, Old A, let me debunk this rumor
老 A，老 A，让我来辟谣。
This is fake.
这是假的。
won't be dismantled
不会被拆除
It hasn't been demolished or touched.
它既没有被拆除，也没有被改动。
Then they negotiated with us
然后他们和我们进行了谈判。
and is willing to do business properly
并且愿意合法经营。
willing to do business properly now
现在愿意正规地做生意
Yeah
是的
The glance actually invited the delegation, the delegation went.
那一眼神仿佛在邀请代表团，代表团欣然前往。
The eyes are clear again
眼睛又清澈了。
That's really not easy
那真不容易。
Oh my god, hiss, sigh, it's so simple
我的天啊，嘶嘶，叹息，这太简单了
He's not in this business
他不做这行。
If it weren't for back then, just everyone look at the map
如果不是因为当时的情况，大家就看看地图吧。
just look south of Poland
看看波兰南部就知道了。
Hungary and Austria
匈牙利和奥地利
mainly because Austria was difficult to build
主要原因是奥地利建设困难。
because Austria is mountainous
因为奥地利是多山的。
Then when you enter Poland, it's all plains
然后当你进入波兰，眼前就全是平原了。
and it's closer to several major European economies
而且它距离几个主要的欧洲经济体更近。
So the location was generally chosen in Poland at that time
所以当时选址通常都在波兰。
That was giving you face
那让你难堪
You should take Old Zhong's offer
你应该接受钟老先生的提议。
Lao Zhong is giving you face
老钟给你脸
Hey, you really think Austria can't build it, huh?
嘿，你真认为奥地利造不出来吗？
It's just not needed, sigh.
唉，完全没必要。
Well sometimes it actually doesn't matter if it's demolished
其实有时候，它被拆除与否其实并不重要。
The China-Europe Railway freight volume is over 5 million tons, right?
中欧铁路货运量超过 500 万吨，对吧？
a year or how many billion
一年或多少亿
Anyway, it accounts for less than 1% of China's total trade volume.
总之，它只占中国贸易总额的不到 1%。
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
it's just a dessert
这只是一道甜点。
and it's relatively insignificant compared to all freight transportation
与所有货运相比，它相对来说微不足道。
it's more of a political gesture and performance
这更像是一种政治姿态和表演。
it can serve as a substitute
它可以作为替代品。
it's like, uh, telling you
这就像，呃，告诉你
That is to say, when there is a need for this thing in the future
也就是说，当将来需要这个东西的时候
It can be replaced
它可以被替换
Don't you take yourself too seriously.
别太把自己当回事。
According to local media reports
据当地媒体报道
an internet
互联网
The model won the anti-drone network bid in Kherson
该模型在赫尔松的反无人机网络招标中胜出。
Can anyone tell me how he how he managed to do that
谁能告诉我他是怎么做到的？他是怎么做到的？
worth 6.3 million hryvnias
价值 630 万格里夫纳
registered as a self-employed individual in July
7 月份注册为个体经营者
and immediately won the bid
并立即赢得了竞标
Wow
哇
Isn't this just too awesome
这简直太棒了！
Is this a sign that the nation is about to perish?
这是国家即将灭亡的征兆吗？
it's like monsters everywhere
到处都是怪物。
Damn
该死
That's fucking awesome
太棒了
found a big brother to rely on
找到了一个可以依靠的大哥
Probably got hooked up with some big shot
可能跟某个大人物搭上了线。
That's pretty impressive
那真是令人印象深刻。
A while ago, the guy who rents out test cars at my place mentioned it.
不久前，我这里出租试驾车的那个人提到了这件事。
I suspect it's going to be sold in Europe, isn't it?
我猜它会在欧洲销售，对吧？
That's probably the case
很可能就是这样。
Ah, I'm fed up
啊，我受够了。
I really am
我真的是
Really?
真的吗？
Someone said hold on, let me check if there's one more
有人说等等，让我看看还有没有另一个。
Let me see if there are any pictures I haven't posted yet.
我看看还有没有上传过的照片。
This is for sorrow
这是为了悲伤
Indian media posted this, and the Japanese might be triggered again.
印度媒体发布了这条消息，日本人可能又要被激怒了。
He's about to be roasted by the Indians, wow
他要被印第安人队狠狠羞辱了，哇！
Well, of course
当然
You're asking whether Indian products are actually of good quality
您是在问印度产品的质量是否真的好。
That's indeed not good
那确实不好。
but it has indeed surpassed you
但它确实已经超越了你。
Ah, now now the Japanese are gonna lose it again.
啊，日本人又要崩溃了。
was overtaken by India
被印度超越
Sigh
叹
Although this Indian ship is a bit shabby, right
虽然这艘印度船有点破旧，对吧？
but it was indeed copied
但它的确是被复制的。
You could say that quantity is quality to some extent, and that's indeed the case.
可以说，数量在某种程度上就是质量，而事实也的确如此。
Quantity is a prerequisite for quality.
数量是质量的前提。
If they don't replace the notebook with some old folks team
如果他们不把笔记本电脑换成一些老家伙的团队呢？
this Comics
这本漫画
The only issue is that the Japanese are drawn too young, right?
唯一的问题是日本人画得太年轻了，对吧？
The average age of Japanese people is not that young.
日本人的平均年龄并不算年轻。
Sigh, thank you Feng Zhong Construction.
唉，谢谢丰忠建设。
Big Brother Media Flow's tip
老大哥媒体流的提示
What is this again?
这是什么来着？
Wait, let me take a look
等等，让我看看
the female Bandera from the 4th Brigade of the Ukrainian National Guard
来自乌克兰国民警卫队第 4 旅的女班德拉
asked what Ukraine is most lacking in terms of personnel
问及乌克兰在人员方面最缺乏什么
First of all, it's people
首先，是人。
The problem isn't a lack of personnel
问题不在于人员短缺。
but rather that these people are quickly depleted
但更确切地说，这些人很快就会被消耗殆尽。
So you Ukraine
所以，乌克兰
the current quality of personnel and main weaponry
目前人员素质和主要武器装备
That indeed gets used up fast
那确实很快就会用完。
What can we do about it?
我们能做些什么？
Sigh, isn't this something you
唉，这难道不是你……
Isn't this what you Ukrainians brought upon yourselves?
这难道不是你们乌克兰人咎由自取吗？
Then what should we do?
那我们该怎么办？
Damn it
该死的
Some say it's such a stereotypical look
有人说这是一种非常刻板的外貌
This look isn't stereotypical enough
这种造型还不够典型。
Someone said this look is a stereotypical Eastern European appearance, what does that look like
有人说这种长相是典型的东欧人长相，那到底是什么样的东欧人长相呢？
Let me show you an even more stereotypical one
让我给你展示一个更典型的例子。
Eagle, you know what the funniest thing is?
老鹰，你知道最搞笑的是什么吗？
Well, according to Ukraine's own statistics
嗯，根据乌克兰自己的统计数据来看。
the population that may have been lost has reached
可能已经消失的人口数量已经达到
around 14 million or so
大约 1400 万左右
According to its own statistics, the number has already reached this figure.
根据其自身统计，该数字已经达到这个数额。
That's normal
这是正常的
Hey wait a sec, let me show you guys
嘿，等一下，让我给你们看看。
Let me show you guys what the most classic Eastern European white girl looks like
让我来给你们展示一下最典型的东欧白人女孩长什么样。
This is the most stereotypical Eastern European blonde girl
这是最典型的东欧金发女郎形象。
like this, um
像这样，嗯
Hold on
坚持，稍等
Ah, take a look at this
啊，看看这个
19 years old, no bride price, can cook Chinese
19 岁，无彩礼，会做中餐
food, choose me or the Chinese girl
食物，选我还是那个中国女孩
This kind of appearance is the standard, right?
这种外观是标准配置，对吧？
standard Eastern European escort
标准东欧伴游
Of course
当然
This is before and after marriage, which is a different story.
这是婚前婚后的情况，婚后的情况就完全不同了。
After marriage, gaining weight post-wedding is a whole different story.
婚后体重增加则是完全不同的情况。
Alright, um
好的，嗯
It will develop into another state
它将发展成另一种状态
It's just like the state of a Russian auntie.
这简直就像俄罗斯阿姨的状态。
also saying heart-throbbing, heart-throbbing, heart-throbbing words
也说些令人心跳加速、令人心跳加速、令人心跳加速的词语
19 years old with zero dowry, can cook Chinese food
19 岁，无嫁妆，会做中餐
Coming to Northeast China, huh?
来中国东北地区吗？
Ah, there's also the comment section, right?
啊，还有评论区呢，对吧？
Share the most hilarious thing that happened during a blind date
分享一次相亲中最搞笑的经历
Look at this, some 'little fairy' just couldn't hold it in anymore
瞧瞧，某个“小仙女”再也忍不住了
Sigh
叹
Someone asked if it's a dietary issue
有人问这是否是饮食问题。
Yeah
是的
It must be due to dietary issues in frigid regions.
这一定是寒冷地区饮食习惯造成的。
I said why haven't I seen anyone go to Heihe when I'm in Northeast China
我问，为什么我在中国东北的时候，没看到有人去黑河？
to Heilongjiang
Northeast is a concept with a vast regional scope
东北是一个涵盖范围极广的概念。
Got it
知道了
Oops
糟糕
You said all four of Trump's wives are blonde bombshells
你说特朗普的四个妻子都是金发尤物
Eastern European appearance
东欧人的外貌
More or less
或多或少
Eastern European features are indeed attractive
东欧人的特色确实很有吸引力。
Fairy exhaling huh
仙女呼气了？
Is it normal not to pant?
不喘气正常吗？
Ah, let them breathe out
啊，让他们呼气吧
Someone said they wanted to go to Heihe
有人说他们想去黑河。
Now it's already visa-free
现在已经免签了。
Go to Heihe? What are you thinking?
去黑河？你在想什么？
Really go to Heihe
真的要去黑河
Don't be afraid, bros.
别害怕，兄弟们。
Yeah, Shenyang has it too, right
对，沈阳也有，对吧？
Shenyang, Harbin, and Changchun all have
沈阳、哈尔滨和长春都有
Go to Heihe to find, uh
去黑河找，呃
You you want to find that kind of naive little girl who's easiest to fool, right?
你想找的是那种最容易上当受骗的天真小女孩，对吧？
to Heihe
前往黑河
Well, they're kinda dumb, right?
他们确实有点笨，对吧？
They're all a bit dumb, right?
他们都有点笨，对吧？
Far Eastern country bumpkin, huh?
远东乡巴佬吧？
Well, the country bumpkin from the Far East has never seen the world
嗯，这个来自远东的乡巴佬从未见过世界。
thinking that Shenyang is just Shenyang
以为沈阳就是沈阳。
Harbin is considered a big city
哈尔滨被认为是一座大城市。
easy to fool, hmm
很容易被骗，嗯。
Someone said the 'little fairy' thinks she's overstepping her bounds, huh?
有人说这位“小仙女”觉得自己越界了，是吗？
What the hell is a 'little fairy'
“小仙女”到底是什么鬼？
Ignore them
别理他们
Who do you think can easily deceive others?
你认为谁最容易欺骗他人？
Don't worry
不用担心
He can't fool you
他骗不了你
The foreign exchange authority will step in.
外汇管理部门将介入。
He can't trick you
他骗不了你
You think too much
你想太多了。
They said to book the flight now
他们说现在就订机票。
Come quickly
快来
There are plenty in Harbin.
哈尔滨有很多。
Harbin has plenty, really plenty
哈尔滨有很多，真的很多。
Sometimes the body odor is unbearable
有时体味令人难以忍受。
Little fairy cleans your family fortune
小仙女净化你的家族财富
Can you stand it
你能忍受吗？
fairy maiden domestic violence against you
仙女少女对你实施家庭暴力
Can you stand it
你能忍受吗？
The little fairy wants to take your property
小仙女想夺走你的财产
Can you stand it
你能忍受吗？
Can body odor be treated with surgery?
体味可以通过手术治疗吗？
Got it
知道了
Some people just can't tell who's the boss and who's not.
有些人就是分不清谁是老板谁不是。
Some people simply can't distinguish what's what
有些人就是分不清什么是什么是什么是
What's the point
有什么意义呢？
just mentioned that thing
刚才提到了那件事
Hey
嘿
19 years old, no dowry, can cook Chinese food
19 岁，无嫁妆，会做中餐
19 years old, zero dowry, can cook Chinese food, choose me or a Chinese girl
19 岁，无嫁妆，会做中餐，选我还是选中国女孩
So
所以
Let's assume he has it
假设他有
And then
进而
Also, you dislike someone for having body odor
此外，你还会因为某人有体味而讨厌他/她。
First of all, you have to be qualified to sleep with them, right?
首先，你得有资格和她们睡觉，对吧？
they sleep with you
他们和你睡在一起
Only then do you have the right to complain about body odor
只有到了那个时候，你才有权抱怨体味。
Some people just don't use their brains at all.
有些人根本不动脑子。
19 years old, zero dowry, can cook Chinese food
19 岁，无嫁妆，会做中餐
that brain
那个大脑
You can't tell if he's been overly conditioned
你无法判断他是否过度训练了。
or is he fucking mentally challenged
还是他脑子有问题？
as soon as you mention someone having body odor
一旦你提到某人有体味，就会引发争议。
They haven't even slept with you yet
他们甚至还没跟你睡过呢
You really don't have to be so... you know what I mean.
你真的不必那么……你知道我的意思。
And Alipay has received 168 yuan
支付宝已收到 168 元人民币。
And body odor is something that can be treated with surgery.
体味可以通过手术治疗。
How much could the surgery possibly cost?
手术费用可能是多少？
Well, thank you, bro, for the super chat and joining the membership!
兄弟，谢谢你的超级留言和加入会员！
Thanks, bro
谢谢兄弟
Thanks to Brother Fengzhu Construction Media Hot for the reward
感谢风竹兄弟建设传媒热度提供的奖励
Let me also show you guys these Russians, these Russian people
我还想让你们看看这些俄罗斯人，这些俄罗斯人。
Where did you collect all these?
这些东西你是从哪里收集到的？
This Sword Saint bro has watched quite a lot, hasn't he?
这位剑圣兄弟看的还真不少啊！
Hmm, it seems Brother Jian Sheng has been following quite a lot usually.
嗯，看来建生哥平时关注得挺多的。
Some people just open their mouths and say things
有些人张口就说些什么
I just think his brain might be, like, retarded.
我只是觉得他脑子可能有点问题。
Don't make me look down on you too much, okay?
别让我太瞧不起你，好吗？
The first thing they talk about is body odor and whatnot.
他们首先谈论的就是体味之类的东西。
sigh
叹
WeChat payment received 20 yuan, mm-hmm
微信支付收到 20 元，嗯哼
Thanks bro
谢谢兄弟
Thanks for the tip, bro
谢谢你的建议，兄弟。
I'm just afraid there are too many simps.
我只是担心舔狗太多了。
turning the Russian girl into a delicate fairy
将俄罗斯女孩变成一个娇弱的仙女
refer to Korean won
指韩元
A bunch of idiots flattering Kao Sir have made him float away.
一群白痴奉承高先生，把他弄得飘走了。
Do you want to know what Foods are available in Heihe?
你想知道黑河有哪些美食吗？
Heihe has all the Northeastern Foods
黑河拥有所有东北食品
Since it's a border city
因为它是一座边境城市
So, in fact, it has all the foods from various regions across Northeast China.
所以，实际上，它包含了中国东北各地所有地区的特色美食。
Of course, you can say whether it's authentic or not
当然，你可以判断它是否是真品。
definitely not that authentic
绝对不是那么真实
but they do have them all, um
但他们确实全都有，嗯。
If you say you want to eat a place that summarizes Northeastern Foods
如果你说你想去一家能概括东北美食的餐厅吃饭
It's indeed a good choice to go to Heihe.
去黑河确实是个不错的选择。
And Heihe's Russian cuisine is also quite good.
黑河的俄罗斯菜也相当不错。
Don't look down on Heihe just because it's a small, old, and rundown little city
不要因为黑河是个小而破旧的老城就小瞧它。
The Russian cuisine in Heihe is indeed quite good.
黑河的俄罗斯菜确实相当不错。
Thank you, bro, for the tip
谢谢兄弟的提醒
This one doesn't have a name written on it again
这个上面又没有写名字了。
Damn, let me scroll down and take a look
糟糕，让我往下翻翻看看。
Why is there no name again?
为什么又没有名字了？
Ah, thank you Brother Yuhao for the reward
啊，谢谢宇豪哥的奖励。
Yes yes yes yes
是的是的是的
See, what did I tell you, right?
你看，我跟你说过什么来着？
this
这
Right?
正确的？
The state will intervene, right?
国家会介入的，对吧？
What foreign woman scams 138,000 dowry through fake marriage
一名外国女子通过假结婚骗取了 13.8 万嫁妆。
Foreign woman arrested while attempting to illegally cross the border after scamming 138,000 yuan in bride price through fake marriage
一名外国女子通过假结婚骗取 13.8 万元彩礼后，试图非法越境时被捕。
See that? See that?
看到了吗？看到了吗？
Ah, that looks good
啊，看起来不错
When will there be a chance to go to Heihe and try the Maomao sister's Russian cuisine
什么时候有机会去黑河尝尝毛毛姐妹做的俄罗斯菜呢？
Let's try some Russian cuisine together
我们一起来尝尝俄罗斯菜吧。
Come on, come on
快点，快点
Uh-huh, I know this is absolutely certain.
嗯哼，我知道这一点绝对确定。
Where did you say this foreign woman is from? Just so-so, you see.
你刚才说这位外国女士是哪里人？也就那样吧。
This is Gansu legal and political affairs
这是甘肃省的法律和政治事务。
Ah, Gansu, that's usually the case, right?
啊，甘肃，通常都是这样，对吧？
Yeah
是的
stayed at the victim's home for less than three days
在受害者家中停留不到三天。
It's generally Vietnamese
通常是越南语
The foreign exchange bureau doesn't mess around with you.
外汇兑换处不会跟你开玩笑。
you know
你知道
The foreign exchange bureau strikes hard
外汇管理局严厉打击
Someone asked, 'Grandpa, have you ever tried American local cuisine?'
有人问：“爷爷，您尝过美国地方菜吗？”
How does it taste
它什么味
Tasted average, yeah
味道一般，是的。
Ah, thanks for the donation
啊，谢谢你的捐赠。
Or is it because of the high-altitude food
或者是因为高海拔食物的缘故？
I follow a few Russian YouTubers on Bilibili and overseas platforms
我在哔哩哔哩和海外平台上关注了一些俄罗斯的 YouTube 博主。
The younger generation is almost all male with few females.
年轻一代几乎全是男性，女性很少。
this generation even has seven or eight women
这一代甚至还有七八位女性
but there's only one male descendant
但只有一位男性后裔。
what younger generation
年轻一代
almost all of this generation
几乎这一代人
Uh
呃
This is not a genetic issue
这不是基因问题。
Yes, currently in Russia, there is a tendency to prefer giving birth to boys
是的，目前俄罗斯确实存在重男轻女的趋势。
because there are too few boys
因为男孩太少了。
Now the Russian economy has recovered just a little bit.
现在俄罗斯经济略有复苏。
It's quite normal to have boys.
生男孩是很正常的。
Do you know how scarce men are in Russia?
你知道俄罗斯男人有多少吗？
especially lacking in young men
尤其缺乏年轻男性
Yeah, that's right
是的，没错
There are more women than men.
女性人数比男性多。
Some say boys are more likely to mess around than girls.
有人说男孩比女孩更容易胡闹。
That's true, a lot of them drink themselves to death.
没错，他们很多人都是酗酒而死的。
Someone said this sounds familiar
有人说这听起来很耳熟。
Why does this sound familiar
为什么这听起来这么耳熟？
That's just how the Russians are
俄罗斯人就是这样。
He still hasn't changed this demographic structure
他至今仍未改变这种人口结构。
Russia is seriously short of men.
俄罗斯严重缺兵。
So this is
所以这是
Do you know why the daughters at the Russian border checkpoints
你知道为什么俄罗斯边境检查站的女儿们……
can come in large numbers for matchmaking
可以大量参与配对活动
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Russian men in the Far East region have shorter lifespans
远东地区的俄罗斯男性寿命较短。
Otherwise, they die on the battlefield.
否则，他们就会战死沙场。
Life dedicated to the drinking table
一生奉献于酒桌
Not only the men from the Far East region are sent to war.
并非只有远东地区的男性才会被派往战场。
poor old and young
贫困的老人和年轻人
the impoverished hairy guys from the border regions have all gone to war
边境地区那些贫穷的毛茸茸的家伙们都去打仗了。
The women were all left behind.
所有妇女都被留下了。
just waiting for you
一直在等你
You can now understand it as people in the Heihe area of northeastern China secretly
现在你可以理解为，中国东北黑河地区的人们秘密地
stealing from the Russians
偷窃俄罗斯人的钱财
Got it?
知道了？
The men went to war
男人们奔赴战场
died
死亡
The women took the compensation money and came to find Chinese men.
这些妇女拿着赔偿金去找中国男人。
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
those poor Russian women
那些可怜的俄罗斯妇女
Why can they confidently say 'I don't want a bride price'
为什么她们能自信地说“我不需要彩礼”？
a significant portion of them are their own brothers
其中相当一部分是他们的亲兄弟。
her own father
她自己的父亲
or her previous husband died
或者她的前夫去世了
She has a pension
她有养老金。
to put it in a more regional way
更确切地说，是从一个更地域性的角度来谈。
to some extent, it's like Northeast China
在某种程度上，它有点像中国东北。
is essentially stealing from the Russians' home
这本质上就是从俄罗斯人的家里偷东西。
either dead
要么死了
just moved away
刚搬走
people are gone
人们都走了
Someone said there's a minotaur here
有人说这里有牛头怪。
This is not a cuckold situation
这不是绿帽情境。
that was during World War II, right
那是在二战期间，对吧？
British soldiers are fighting bloody battles on the battlefield, right?
英国士兵正在战场上进行血腥的战斗，对吧？
The British homeland was protected by American soldiers.
英国本土由美国士兵保卫。
Then, then, then, damn it
然后，然后，然后，该死的
right
正确的
This is the current situation in Russia, okay
这就是俄罗斯目前的状况，好的。
Well, Russian women also have something to say
嗯，俄罗斯女性也有话要说。
My man is dead
我的男人死了
Is there a problem if I want to find another man?
如果我想找另一个男人，会有问题吗？
I think Chinese men are quite good.
我觉得中国男人挺好的。
All the local men are dead
当地所有男人都死了
Can't I find a Chinese man?
我找不到中国人吗？
Is this okay
这样可以吗？
That's how it is
就是这样。
A large number of unmarried young women also have money in their pockets
许多未婚年轻女性身上也有钱。
You don't let them get married properly
你不让他们正式结婚。
They will squander this money in places you least want them to.
他们会把这笔钱挥霍在你最不希望他们挥霍的地方。
all kinds of terrifying entertainment products
各种恐怖娱乐产品
And Russia doesn't produce these things
俄罗斯并不生产这些东西。
Do you know what I'm talking about?
你知道我在说什么吗？
Having them marry a Chinese man is the best outcome
让他们嫁给一个中国男人是最好的结果
Buying bags is actually the better option
购买包袋实际上是更好的选择
You know what I mean
你知道我的意思
You know, the country can provide many things
你知道，这个国家可以提供很多东西。
when you lack food and clothing
当你缺乏食物和衣物时
The state can take care of you
国家会照顾你的。
you lack emotional companionship
你缺乏情感上的陪伴。
The state can't take care of it
国家无力承担。
You're saying you lack male companionship
你是说你缺乏男性陪伴
Russia is most in need of men
俄罗斯最需要男性
They're still needed on the battlefield
战场上仍然需要他们。
You want me to conjure up tens of millions of young men for you in the rear?
你想让我变出几千万个年轻男子到你身后？
Where am I supposed to find young men for you?
我上哪儿去找年轻力壮的小伙子给你？
No
不
You know what?
你知道吗？
No
不
Where am I supposed to find it for you
我该去哪里帮你找呢？
You guys are having such a great opportunity right now
你们现在拥有一个绝佳的机会。
a rare opportunity that comes once in decades, alright
这是几十年才有一次的难得机会，没错。
Go if you can
能去就去吧
Brothers
兄弟
borrow from China
向中国借钱
Right
正确的
Your current situation in the Northeast
您目前在东北部的情况
just borrow from China
直接向中国借钱就行了。
is indeed leaning towards China
确实倾向于中国
That's right.
这是正确的。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
That's just the reality
这就是现实
If if this kind of large-scale marriage migration
如果这种大规模的婚姻移民
if it weren't tacitly approved by the Russian government
如果不是俄罗斯政府默许的话
How could this possibly be achieved?
这怎么可能实现呢？
The local governments on both sides can still collaborate, right?
双方地方政府仍然可以合作，对吗？
Thanks for the reward, bro
谢谢你的奖励，兄弟。
Just finished eating
刚吃完
waiting for the typhoon to make landfall
等待台风登陆
Warn the audience in Guangdong, Guangxi, and Hainan to stay safe
提醒广东、广西、海南的观众注意安全。
Emergency management office, add it on
应急管理办公室，把它加上
Wait a minute for the flowers to Gaza
稍等片刻，鲜花要送到加沙。
The typhoon is described as a catastrophic disaster
这场台风被形容为一场灾难性的灾难。
This is no joke
这可不是开玩笑。
Meanwhile, we'd like to extend our preemptive gratitude to neighboring provinces preparing to aid Guangdong and Guangxi
与此同时，我们谨向准备援助广东和广西的邻近省份提前表达我们的谢意。
Friends from the Fujian and Hainan rescue teams
来自福建和海南救援队的朋友们
I hope everyone stays safe
希望大家都平安无事。
a DJ version of
DJ 版本
Silent Years, okay?
沉默的岁月，好吗？
There's even a DJ version of this
甚至还有这首歌的 DJ 版本。
Hope everyone doesn't actually get too hyped up while streaming.
希望大家在直播的时候不要太激动。
Just keep streaming
继续播放
Just finished eating and waiting for the tailor.
刚吃完饭，正在等裁缝。
open um ah
打开嗯啊
Hope everyone doesn't spend money
希望大家都不要花钱
Just broadcast until one minute and three seconds is fine
广播到一分零三秒即可。
One minute and three seconds, really?
一分零三秒？真的吗？
Brother Shen Ying's little tune
沈英哥的小曲
How about that
怎么样？
Leaderboard
排行榜
Hey
嘿
Shenying, Brother Shenying's little song, how's that?
沈鹰，沈鹰哥的小歌，怎么样？
Ah, thank you Wind Sword Saint and Student Bro for gifting the Belarusian beauty.
啊，感谢风剑圣徒和学弟赠送这位白俄罗斯美女。
A thousand cups of wine have been drunk, yet none are right.
喝了一千杯酒，却没有一杯是对的。
Autumn wind and rain stand in contrast
秋风雨与之形成鲜明对比。
Dare not say it out loud
不敢大声说出来
dare to confront
敢于面对
Powerless, ignorant, and heartless
无能、无知、冷酷无情
This silence is still stirring
这片寂静依然令人心潮澎湃。
Let me see
让我看看
Also, let me tell you guys
还有，让我告诉你们……
This is from the heart in some remote place
这是来自某个偏远地方的肺腑之言
If you marry a Russian girl now
如果你现在娶一个俄罗斯女孩
There's another benefit, especially if you marry someone from the Far East.
还有另一个好处，特别是如果你嫁给来自远东的人。
What's the advantage?
有什么优势？
Ah, that means you can inherit that piece of homestead land.
啊，那意味着你可以继承那块宅基地。
Although Russia doesn't call it a homestead
虽然俄罗斯不称之为家园。
that is, if he is in that kind of rural Far East in Russia
也就是说，如果他身处俄罗斯远东地区的那种农村地带。
Let me tell you guys
让我告诉你们这些家伙
the earliest group of Chinese people who went to farm in Russia
最早一批前往俄罗斯务农的中国人
How did the Chinese who went to Russia to rent greenhouses go there
那些去俄罗斯租温室的中国人是怎么去的？
At the beginning, it wasn't about openly buying land.
一开始，这并不是公开购买土地的事情。
What is usually the case?
通常情况下是什么样的？
he found a woman from the Russian Far East
他找到了一位来自俄罗斯远东地区的女人。
This woman is in a Russian village
这位女士身处俄罗斯的一个村庄。
The land belongs to her parents.
这块地属于她父母。
She came to China to find a man
她来中国是为了找个男人
It's because there are no men there
因为那里没有男人。
He can no longer farm this land
他再也无法耕种这片土地了。
He wants to come to Northeast China to find a Chinese man to help him farm the land.
他想去中国东北找个中国人帮他耕种土地。
Many went there for this reason
很多人就是因为这个原因去的。
After he arrived in the Far East
他抵达远东之后
He has a piece of land
他拥有一块土地。
Chinese people are very diligent in farming.
中国人务农非常勤劳。
great skills
精湛的技能
He gradually ended up contracting all that land
他最终逐渐将所有土地都承包了起来。
and then he gradually transformed from a farmer into a plantation owner
然后，他逐渐从一个农民变成了一个种植园主。
You know what I mean
你知道我的意思
became a landlord
成为房东
Then he contracted more and more land
然后他陆续购买了越来越多的土地。
then they started building greenhouses
然后他们开始建造温室。
Many farmers from Northeast China
中国东北地区的许多农民
in the Russian Far East region
在俄罗斯远东地区
acting as landlords monopolizing the vegetable supply in a region
充当房东，垄断某一地区的蔬菜供应
Ah, there's this benefit
啊，还有这个好处
he allows if you get married
如果你结婚，他允许你结婚
after getting that marriage certificate
拿到结婚证之后
so you can also inherit that land in the Russian Far East, right?
所以你也可以继承俄罗斯远东地区的那块土地，对吧？
You can reclaim the ancestral land in another way, okay?
你可以用其他方式收回祖地，好吗？
Ah
啊
This is also tacitly approved by the Russian government.
俄罗斯政府也对此表示默许。
Otherwise, that land would remain uncultivated.
否则，这片土地将一直荒芜。
Yang is right
哪个是对的
And it can still be like this
而且情况可能仍然如此。
Thanks to Brother Fengshen Jian for the media student's tip
感谢冯申建哥提供的媒体学生线索
Let me show you guys
让我给你们展示一下
Pioneer Warrior ah
先锋战士啊
There are already trailblazers oh
已经有开拓者了哦
Is it sometimes allowed to purchase domestically?
有时是否允许在国内购买？
For example, him
例如，他
He usually is, is, is the local government
他通常是，是，是地方政府
He doesn't buy
他不买
it's usually done through under-the-table deals
这通常是通过私下交易完成的。
it's not so legitimate
这不太合法
Sometimes eating so well, uh
有时候吃得太好，呃
I guess so
大概吧
Does that guy count as a woman?
那个人算女人吗？
Is this considered a foreign male steak, huh?
这算是外国男性牛排吗？
That's quite a name you've got there, huh?
你这名字可真够特别的，是吧？
That's really how it is in Russia
俄罗斯的情况确实如此。
that is, the younger brother is not under your name
也就是说，弟弟的姓氏不属于你。
is under your wife's name
登记在你妻子名下
but the crops you grow are for selling
但你种的庄稼是为了卖的。
it's your own
这是你自己的
The main thing is that everyone should be able to see
最重要的是，每个人都应该能够看到
Don't just see the thief eating meat
不要只看到小偷在吃肉
Farming is no easy task.
务农并非易事。
Yes, indeed
是的，确实如此
You need to have a routine, right
你需要养成规律的生活习惯，对吧？
Got this opportunity, right?
抓住这个机会吧？
Alipay received 20 yuan. Hmm
支付宝收到了 20 元。嗯。
Although Northeast China and Siberia
尽管中国东北和西伯利亚
that land is relatively flat and fertile
那片土地相对平坦且肥沃。
Then farming is not an easy job either.
那么，务农也不是一件容易的事。
Uh, thank you Little Xuan Bro for the tip.
呃，谢谢小宣哥的提醒。
Let me check, um
让我查一下，嗯
S, um, WeChat payment received 20 yuan, um
S，嗯，微信支付收到 20 元，嗯
Brothers, share a little fairy tale from around me
兄弟们，分享一个我身边的小童话故事吧。
If I had a childhood friend who studied liberal arts
如果我有一个儿时的朋友学习文科的话
His family runs a law firm.
他家经营一家律师事务所。
got into a 211 university after repeating a year
重读一年后考入了一所 211 大学。
At the farewell banquet we held for him before he left for college in another city
在他前往另一个城市上大学之前，我们为他举办了告别宴会。
That confidence as if life is completely in his hands
他那份自信，仿佛生命完全掌握在他手中。
beauties will throw themselves into his arms
美丽的姑娘们会投怀送抱
As soon as he started college, he got hammered by a little fairy.
他刚上大学就被一个小仙女狠狠地揍了一顿。
How about that
怎么样？
In his first month of college, he encountered a senior female student
大学第一个月，他就遇到了一位高年级的女学生。
They were extremely notorious in the college.
他们在大学里臭名昭著。
His academic advisor advised him not to date that girl.
他的学术顾问建议他不要和那个女孩约会。
But somehow he got it into his head
但不知怎的，他把这事记在了脑子里。
I ended up agreeing to it, and the little fairy was the one who pursued her first.
我最终同意了，而且是那个小仙女先追求她的。
Well, that's not surprising.
这倒也不奇怪。
After dating for a month
交往一个月后
found out that the fairy had already gotten married
得知仙女已经结婚了。
And what's more, it was my childhood friend who accompanied that fairy to handle it
更重要的是，陪同那位仙女去处理这件事的，竟然是我的儿时好友。
got a divorce
离婚了
paralyzed for three months
瘫痪三个月
couldn't stand it anymore
我再也忍受不了了
on-and-off relationship with the fairy-like girl
与仙女般女孩分分合合的关系
all sorts of fairy-like remarks during that period
那段时间里出现了各种各样如童话般的言论。
Even I cringe at it.
连我看了都觉得尴尬。
And that's not all
但这还不是全部
Less than two weeks after my childhood friend went crazy
我的儿时好友发疯后不到两周，我就疯了。
Let me see, less than two weeks
让我想想，不到两周
Let me see
让我看看
what's up
这是怎么回事
Not interested yet hooked up with another freshman guy again.
没兴趣，但又跟另一个大一新生搞上了。
A freshman added my childhood friend as a contact one day and then
有一天，一个大一新生把我儿时的朋友加为联系人，然后
scolded my friend harshly
我严厉地训斥了我的朋友
Who knows what kind of love potion the little fairy fed that guy
谁知道小仙女给那家伙喝了什么爱情药水。
I can only say my childhood friend still has a clear mind and didn't get involved
我只能说，我的儿时好友头脑依然清醒，没有卷入此事。
otherwise who knows if the little fairy would scam money
否则谁知道那小仙女会不会骗钱呢。
or has some other issues
或者还有其他问题
cut losses in time
及时止损
dump the goods immediately
立即倾倒货物
My childhood friend is honest
我的童年好友很诚实
psychological shadow
心理阴影
He didn't date anyone for all four years of college
大学四年期间，他一直没有谈恋爱。
Not strange, right?
不奇怪，对吧？
super scary
超级恐怖
being in a second marriage by senior year
大四那年再婚
That is to say, the first marriage is already over.
也就是说，第一次婚姻已经结束了。
Ah, thank you Brother Feng Shen, the construction media student, for the tip!
啊，谢谢建筑媒体专业的冯申哥提供的信息！
As long as you promise to date a Far East Russian beauty
只要你答应和一位远东俄罗斯美女约会就行了
Dressing like this for a date can increase your chances of success
约会时这样打扮可以增加你成功的几率。
Which train is this? Oh man.
这是哪趟列车？我的天。
Is this okay
这样可以吗？
I am not Napoleon
我不是拿破仑
Let me take a look
让我看看
Well, the lands of Siberia and Outer Northeast
嗯，西伯利亚和东北外围地区
Only in winter when the ground is frozen hard
只有在冬天，当地面冻得坚硬的时候。
the machinery can enter
机器可以进入
Then leave it for the winter
然后把它留到冬天。
In May, when spring arrives, the land is leveled and cleared again.
五月春天到来时，土地再次被平整和清理出来。
and then another year
然后又过了一​​年
You can only officially sow the seeds in the third spring.
只有在第三个春天才能正式播种。
As for the harvest, it depends on the weather, hmm.
至于收成，那就得看天气了，嗯。
The cost here includes three years of time and the expenses for pesticides and machinery.
这里的成本包括三年的时间以及农药和机械设备的费用。
Not as high as you might think
没你想象的那么高
as long as you buy it from China
只要你从中国购买就行了
Oh man
哦，天哪
Seriously, I'm fed up
说真的，我受够了。
Seriously, bros
说真的，兄弟们
Don't be fooled
别被骗了
Don't be fooled by those fairies.
别被那些仙女骗了。
I feel so exhausted today
我今天感觉好累
I'm really exhausted after Auto-Play Next for three days.
连续三天使用自动播放功能，我真的累坏了。
Auto-Play Next for a bit too long
自动播放下一曲的时间有点长了。
But there's no other choice
但别无选择
Oops, wrong one.
哎呀，选错了。
Oops
糟糕
Let me see
让我看看
Thank you for the tip
谢谢你的提醒
Not necessarily compensation
不一定是补偿
Few cases of domestic violence among male students at Tohoku University
东北大学男学生家庭暴力案件极少
can do housework
能做家务
high proportion of RVs
RVs 比例高
pay generously
慷慨支付
Uh uh
嗯嗯
Someone asked how long I sleep every day
有人问我每天睡多久
this little broadcast uh
这个小广播呃
I just slept for three hours before going Live with you guys.
我刚睡了三个小时就和你们一起直播了。
feeling alright
感觉还不错
Feed the monkeys today
今天喂猴子
What to feed today
今天喂什么
Monkeys don't feed monkeys
猴子不喂猴子
monkey feeding monkey
猴子喂猴子
This job doesn't belong to me anymore, you get it?
这份工作已经不属于我了，你明白吗？
Oh dear
哦亲爱的
Ah, I'll open this window of mine
啊，我这就打开我的窗户。
Although the weather is still a bit cold now
虽然现在天气还是有点冷
but let's open the window for some ventilation
不过，我们还是打开窗户通风吧。
can help relieve
可以帮助缓解
Are we building Gunpla today?
今天我们要拼装高达模型吗？
The Gundam has already been assembled.
高达已经组装完毕。
No need for me
我不需要你
So you're saying let the junior handle the junior's tasks, right?
所以你的意思是让资历浅的员工去做他/她该做的事情，对吗？
No need for me
我不需要你
It's already the junior's job
这已经是初级员工的工作了。
It has nothing to do with me
这跟我一点关系都没有。
Sigh, sometimes I even go and play, uh
唉，有时候我甚至还会去玩，呃……
Bro, you might not know
兄弟，你可能不知道
The Gundam mentioned in this Live is not the Gundam you think it is
这次直播中提到的高达并不是你想的那台高达。
Right?
正确的？
That is to say, new viewers in this Live
也就是说，本次直播的新观众
might not yet know what I mean by Gundam
可能还不明白我说的高达是什么意思。
Alright, um
好的，嗯
This, this Gundam is a full-scale one-to-one replica.
这台高达是 1:1 全尺寸复制品。
one-to-one ratio, okay
一对一的比例，好的
When I'm talking about Gundam
当我谈到高达的时候
Generally not referring to the toy version, you know
通常不是指玩具版本，你知道的。
refers to some more, uh, more something versions, okay
指的是一些更……嗯……更丰富的版本，好的。
Alright, let me see
好的，让我看看
Today we can talk about
今天我们可以谈谈
Let's get straight to the point today, shall we?
今天我们就直奔主题吧？
Hey, let's talk about the medical treatment process in the U.S.
嘿，我们来聊聊美国的医疗流程吧。
And why is medical care in the U.S. so frustrating?
为什么美国的医疗保健如此令人沮丧？
Why do many tumor patients prefer to fly back to their home country for treatment
为什么许多肿瘤患者更愿意飞回自己的国家接受治疗
don't seek medical treatment in the U.S.
不要在美国寻求医疗救治
Let me start by saying
首先我想说的是……
It's an old cliché
这是一句老生常谈。
probably everyone has some notion and impression about this matter
可能每个人都对此事有一些想法和印象。
Take a guess
猜猜看
For example, if I'm feeling unwell today
例如，如果我今天感觉不舒服
I'm feeling unwell today
我今天感觉不太舒服。
I'm sick today
我今天生病了
I want to see a doctor
我想去看医生
So about how long would it take for me to see a doctor?
那我大概需要多久才能见到医生？
Take a guess, everyone
大家猜猜看。
Ah, thank you for the tip from the beautiful original creator Brother Feng Zhi Jiansheng!
啊，感谢美丽的原创作者冯志建生兄的推荐！
This is also a Russian
这也是俄罗斯的
You're lying to me
你在骗我
Why are the Russian beauties I found all lacking in headlight size?
为什么我遇到的那些俄罗斯美女车，前大灯的尺寸都偏小？
Could it be your problem, hmm
会不会是你的问题呢？嗯？
a week ten days a month uh
一周十天，一个月，呃
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
generally speaking
一般来说
For example, if I want to see a doctor on the 1st of this month
例如，如果我想在这个月 1 号去看医生。
I'm sick
我生病了
So, how long will it most likely take for me to see this doctor?
那么，我大概需要多久才能见到这位医生？
Depending on the department
根据部门而定
depending on the severity
根据严重程度而定
I probably need to wait about 30 days or so
我可能需要等大约 30 天左右。
that's four work weeks
那是四个工作周
that's 20 working days before I can get an appointment
我得等 20 个工作日才能预约。
On average, it's about a month.
平均来说，大约需要一个月。
This still depends on whether you are that or what
这仍然取决于你是那样的人还是什么人。
you're not being seen by some particularly scarce doctors
你没能见到一些特别难找的医生。
such as cardiothoracic surgery or neurosurgery
例如心胸外科手术或神经外科手术
like liver
像肝脏
vital organs like the lungs
肺等重要器官
If you want to see doctors in these specialties
如果你想看这些专科的医生
a month and a half or two months
一个半月到两个月
It could take up to three months.
可能需要长达三个月的时间。
What kind of situation is it
这是什么情况？
It's like minor illnesses don't need treatment
就好像小病不需要治疗一样。
Serious illnesses cannot be cured
重病无法治愈
This is where we're not talking about any quality
这里我们讨论的并非任何质量问题。
We're not discussing any prices
我们不讨论任何价格。
Let's just talk about time, that's about it.
我们就谈谈时间吧，仅此而已。
Are underground clinics sometimes faster?
地下诊所有时速度更快吗？
but the quality isn't guaranteed
但质量无法保证。
there's no guarantee of safety either
安全也无法得到保证。
And let me tell you guys
让我告诉你们这些家伙
seeking medical treatment in the US
在美国寻求医疗救治
Medical treatment in Europe and America is generally like this
欧洲和美国的医疗待遇通常如下：
During the process of seeking medical treatment
在寻求医疗救治的过程中
Do you know how many parties are actually involved in this?
你知道这件事实际上涉及多少方吗？
it's three parties
这是三方会谈。
Let me tell you
让我告诉你
not just you and the medical side
不仅仅是你和医疗方面的问题
it's a matter between the two parties, the hospital and the other side
这是医院和对方双方之间的事情。
No
不
there are three parties in total
总共有三个政党。
And who else is there?
还有谁？
It's the insurance company, ah! The insurance company has to get involved.
啊，是保险公司！保险公司必须介入。
Let me first talk about your health insurance
首先让我谈谈您的健康保险。
Because in the United States, the government
因为在美国，政府
does not provide universal and inclusive healthcare for all
未能为所有人提供普遍且包容的医疗保健
so everyone has to buy their own insurance
所以每个人都必须自己购买保险。
Everyone has their own different insurance company
每个人都有自己的保险公司。
Everyone has different personalities
每个人都有不同的性格。
The results you get can be completely different.
得到的结果可能完全不同。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
The most damn thing about seeing a doctor in the US is
在美国看医生最让人头疼的就是
Not only is it difficult to see a doctor
不仅看医生很困难。
For example, I went through all kinds of hardships
例如，我经历过各种各样的困难。
I fucking waited for a month
我他妈等了一个月。
I finally got to see the doctor
我终于见到医生了。
The doctor told me
医生告诉我
You've got such and such disease, right?
你得了某种疾病，对吗？
blah blah blah
巴拉巴拉
What kind of medicine do you need to take?
你需要服用哪种药物？
how long to take what and what, there are several options
具体服用多长时间、服用什么药物，有几种选择。
Option one, option two
选项一，选项二
Option 3
选项 3
Option 4 is placed before you
选项 4 放在你面前。
Please remember
请记住
This is not the time for you to choose
现在不是你做出选择的时候。
Your third-party insurance company will immediately intervene
您的第三方保险公司将立即介入。
he clearly tells you
他明确地告诉你
You can only use what medication
你只能使用特定的药物
You can only use Plan X
你只能使用 X 计划。
Why
为什么
If you dare to use any other treatment plan
如果你胆敢使用任何其他治疗方案
what medicine
什么药
I won't reimburse you
我不会赔偿你
You're fine
你没事。
It's just that I won't reimburse you
只是我不会赔偿你。
My medical insurance is not universal in nature
我的医疗保险并非全民保险。
nor is it provided by the state
国家也没有提供这项服务。
You'll have to see if I'm in the mood to reimburse you
你得看我有没有心情报销。
So you're saying, can I use this most effective and expensive medication or not?
所以你的意思是，我到底能不能使用这种疗效最好、价格也最贵的药物？
No
不
Why won't the health insurance cover it?
为什么医疗保险不予报销？
Let me tell you
让我告诉你
In the U.S., healthcare has severe class attributes and class discrimination.
在美国，医疗保健具有严重的阶级属性和阶级歧视。
If you're just an ordinary person
如果你只是一个普通人
purchased a very basic health insurance
购买了一份非常基础的健康保险。
let me tell you
让我告诉你
That kind of discrimination is blatant and undisguised.
这种歧视是明目张胆、毫不掩饰的。
It means you're not worthy of using this medication
这意味着你不符合使用这种药物的条件。
You can't earn that money back
你不可能把那笔钱赚回来。
Don't even think about it
想都别想。
I won't cover it for you
我不会替你承担这笔费用。
right
正确的
You want me to reimburse you
你想让我赔偿你
You must use such and such treatment plan
你必须使用这样的治疗方案
You must use whatever medication is specified in this treatment plan
您必须使用本治疗方案中指定的任何药物。
you can't even decide how much you want to take
你甚至都无法决定你想拿多少。
You don't have a say in it.
你没有发言权。
And let me tell you
让我告诉你
It's not medical logic
这不符合医学逻辑
For example, you might need to take 20 pills to cure this illness.
例如，你可能需要服用 20 粒药片才能治愈这种疾病。
That's what the doctor said
医生是这么说的。
has nothing to do with my insurance company
这与我的保险公司无关。
I won't cover 20 pills for you
我不会替你付 20 片药的钱。
I might only cover ten pills for you
我可能只能帮你付十片药的钱。
You'll have to pay the full price for the remaining pills.
剩余的药片你需要支付全价。
Got it?
知道了？
It's purely financial logic
这纯粹是金融逻辑。
but not medical logic
但并非医学逻辑
medical logic
医学逻辑
This is the most terrifying aspect of seeking medical care in the U.S.
这是在美国寻求医疗服务最令人恐惧的方面。
which is the involvement of a third party
这就是第三方介入的情况。
using medical
使用医疗
replacing medical thinking with financial thinking
用金融思维取代医学思维
and make decisions for you
并替你做决定
Some people might ask why they restrict which medication you can use
有些人可能会问，为什么他们会限制你可以使用的药物种类。
First, your insurance company can also earn commissions
首先，你的保险公司也可以赚取佣金。
not only does he want to make money off you
他不仅想从你身上赚钱。
He also makes money from pharmaceutical companies
他还从制药公司赚钱。
I specify that you can only use a certain treatment plan
我明确规定您只能使用特定的治疗方案。
the drugs under this treatment plan
该治疗方案中的药物
I'll reimburse
我会偿还。
Then you have to take more of this medicine.
那么你就得服用更多这种药了。
Someone said
有人说
Then wouldn’t he have to spend money if he reimburses it?
如果他偿还这笔费用，难道他不需要花钱吗？
The pharmaceutical company, this drug company, has to give me a kickback.
这家制药公司，这家药厂，必须给我回扣。
because I recommended him to use your medicine
因为我建议他使用你的药。
He's not at a loss
他并不感到迷茫
Some international students say they don't feel this way
有些国际学生表示他们没有这种感觉。
Bullshit
废话
Your insurance is very expensive
你的保险费用很高。
you also have more treatment options
您还有更多治疗选择。
your health insurance company usually won't directly tell you
你的医疗保险公司通常不会直接告诉你。
You can't use it
你不能用它
Well, it's just that, you know, the pain of seeking medical treatment in the U.S. is like this
嗯，你知道，在美国寻求医疗救治的痛苦就是这么来的。
not just the alienation of healthcare by capital
不仅仅是资本对医疗保健的异化
What else?
还有什么？
Some people ask, what is class discrimination in medical resources?
有人问，医疗资源中的阶级歧视是什么？
You spent different amounts of money
你花费的金额各不相同。
You bought different insurance policies from different insurance companies, right?
你从不同的保险公司购买了不同的保险单，对吗？
People's insurance plans are divided into three, six, nine grades.
人们的保险计划分为三级、六级、九级。
Let me tell you
让我告诉你
Hospitals will judge your treatment based on your insurance plan.
医院会根据您的保险计划来决定您的治疗方案。
What does it mean to judge a dish by its insurance coverage?
根据菜肴的保险覆盖范围来评判其品质意味着什么？
your $5000 a month insurance and $1000 a month insurance
你每月 5000 美元的保险和每月 1000 美元的保险
and the $500-a-month and $50-a-month insurance plans all exist
每月 500 美元和每月 50 美元的保险计划都存在。
When it's 5,000 yuan per month
每月 5000 元人民币的时候
that person with insurance goes to the hospital
有保险的人去了医院。
all the benefits he can receive
他可以获得的所有好处
is the same as those with five-dollar or fifty-dollar insurance
和那些投保五美元或五十美元保险的人一样。
is completely different
完全不同
I can tell you very responsibly that
我可以非常负责任地告诉你，
The vast majority of hospitals in China treat all patients
中国绝大多数医院都收治所有患者。
basically it's all at the level of 5,000 yuan per month
基本上都在每月 5000 元人民币的水平。
the attitude of doctors at the US dollar level towards patients
医生对患者的态度（以美元计）
Chinese patients
中国患者
In reality, this kind of healthcare discrimination is rarely experienced.
实际上，这种医疗保健歧视现象很少发生。
Ouch
哎哟
Hey, one minute, hello?
嘿，等一下，喂？
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
Come back come back come back
回来，回来，回来
Don't rush
别着急
Don't rush don't rush don't rush
别着急，别着急，别着急
Ah, come back come back come back come back
啊，回来吧回来吧回来吧回来吧
I'm back
我回来了
Sigh, is it still going to be seven days next time?
唉，下次还是要七天吗？
You don't know, right?
你不知道，对吧？
But I need to take it easy.
但我需要放轻松些。
Damn, I'm fed up
该死，我受够了。
Really
真的
Ah, this is so frustrating.
啊，真是太令人沮丧了。
Yes
是的
Tsk, I don't know.
啧，我不知道。
Do any of you actually empathize with this?
你们当中有人能真正感同身受吗？
Do you guys actually empathize with this?
你们真的能感同身受吗？
Holy shit
我的天啊
Oh my god, I'm so done
我的天哪，我彻底崩溃了。
It's just that
只是……
I don't know who's reporting me
我不知道是谁举报了我。
Oh my god
我的天啊
saying Dai Cheng
say silly pure
说傻傻的纯洁
Wow, what the hell other nicknames can be used here?
哇，这里还能用哪些其他昵称？
Let me think about what term to use
让我想想该用什么词。
Damn annoying
真烦人
You know what
你知道吗
I'm right in the middle of speaking passionately
我正在激情澎湃地演讲。
He fucking shot me with a bang
他他妈的砰的一声把我打死了。
stab me twice in the back
我背部被捅了两刀。
Someone said the insurance policy isn't very reliable either
有人说这份保险单也不太可靠。
Sigh
叹
Thank you Jin Jiangqiu Xue for the grid tip
The first day the little kitten came home
小猫回家的第一天
pitiful
可怜
Play this to relax, hmm
放这首歌放松一下，嗯。
Play this haha
玩这个哈哈
Jimmy, please pacify the moderators
吉米，请安抚一下版主们。
Sigh, let's calm down the moderators... ah, how about playing a cute pet video, huh?
唉，咱们还是让版主们冷静一下吧……啊，要不播放一段可爱的宠物视频怎么样？
Appearing on the glass window
出现在玻璃窗上
your broken-hearted world
你那破碎的世界
just ignited my sky with rainbow films surrounding me
仿佛一道彩虹点亮了我的天空，将我包围其中。
Oh, how you're like a little elf!
哦，你简直就像个小精灵！
Hey, I should use Trauma Team, right?
嘿，我应该用创伤小组，对吧？
using the trauma team from 2077
使用来自 2077 年的创伤团队
Yes yes yes
是的，是的，是的
So everyone's trauma team is different, right?
所以每个医院的创伤救治团队都不一样，对吧？
it's the trauma team you hired
那是你雇佣的创伤小组。
The price of the trauma team he hired is different
他雇佣的创伤团队的价格不同。
Got it?
知道了？
Trauma Team, yeah yeah right
创伤小组，是啊是啊
Trauma Team using the Trauma Team from 2077 uh
创伤小组使用来自 2077 年的创伤小组
Perfect, absolutely perfect
完美，绝对完美
Right? Ah
对吧？啊
You are a platinum member
您是白金会员
He is a gold member
他是金牌会员
He is silver
他是银色的
He is bronze
他是青铜
He's the black iron tier
他是黑铁级
right
正确的
Some people say, where does this discrimination lie?
有人问，这种歧视究竟体现在哪里？
He doesn't just discriminate in terms of medical treatment plans
他不仅在医疗方案方面存在歧视。
discrimination in the amount of medication given
在用药量方面存在歧视
There is also discrimination in terms of attitude
在态度方面也存在歧视。
Let me tell you guys first
首先让我告诉你们一下。
it's ingrained in the minds of older Chinese folks
这种观念已经深深根植于中国老年人的脑海中。
mental trauma
精神创伤
Thanks to Brother J for the reward
感谢 J 兄弟的奖励
laughed
笑了
It can't be that some passerby can't afford a trauma team
不可能是某个路人请不起创伤急救队吧。
can't afford medical treatment
负担不起医疗费用
lying paralyzed on the roadside
瘫倒在路边
then got furious upon seeing the Live stream
看到直播后，他勃然大怒
Speaking of which
说到这个
Donut is really tough
甜甜圈真的很难
after being missing online for half a year last year
去年曾有半年时间在网上消失
still alive
仍然活着
Damn impressive
真是令人印象深刻
That's indeed true, I've seen it with my own eyes
的确如此，我亲眼所见。
I've seen it happen in the hospital.
我在医院里亲眼见过这种情况。
First, let's talk about American doctors and uh
首先，我们来谈谈美国医生，嗯……
What's the difference between trauma teams in the United States and China?
美国和中国的创伤救治团队有什么区别？
In the American trauma team
美国创伤团队
How much does the leader of a trauma team earn in a year
创伤小组组长一年能挣多少钱？
not much
不多。
a few million
几百万
just imagine
想象一下
Can the leader of a Chinese trauma team earn millions of dollars?
中国创伤救护队队长能赚到数百万美元吗？
Well, even a few hundred thousand might be hard to come by, right?
嗯，即使是几十万也可能很难筹到，对吧？
If you're not that kind of hospital like Peking Union Medical College Hospital
如果你不是像北京协和医院那样的医院
Well, for that kind of trauma team like in Peking Union Medical College Hospital, right
嗯，对于像北京协和医院那样的创伤团队来说，对吧？
Most team leaders of trauma teams don't earn that much money
大多数创伤小组组长的收入并不高。
So from the perspective of outcome disparity
所以从结果差异的角度来看
He and his patients can often empathize with each other
他和他的病人常常能够互相理解。
can empathize
能够感同身受
But in America, it doesn't work well
但在美国，这种方法效果并不好。
The income of the leader of the trauma team is just way too high, way too high, way too high
创伤小组组长的收入实在太高了，太高了，太高了。
he has absolutely no empathy with his patients
他对病人完全没有同理心。
he is completely unable to empathize with the patient's suffering
他完全无法体会病人的痛苦。
Let me give you the simplest example
我举个最简单的例子。
American doctors
美国医生
The leader of the American trauma team is extremely arrogant.
美国创伤小组的组长极其傲慢。
How condescending is he?
他有多傲慢？
they simply cannot comprehend the struggles of the poor at the bottom
他们根本无法理解底层穷人的苦难。
Why is this happening
为什么会发生这种情况
He said, 'Oh, you have diabetes'
他说：“哦，你有糖尿病。”
Oh, you have high blood pressure
哦，你有高血压。
Oh, you have high blood lipids
哦，你血脂偏高。
the doctor, who is the leader of the trauma team
这位医生是创伤团队的负责人
would casually say to the patient
会随意地对病人说
Why can't you spend two hours every day
为什么你不能每天花两个小时
spare two hours of free time to focus on fitness
抽出两个小时的空闲时间专注于健身
Why do you eat hamburgers?
你为什么吃汉堡？
How unhealthy hamburgers are!
汉堡包有多么不健康啊！
Can't you just eat some salad and imitation sausage?
你就不能吃点沙拉和人造香肠吗？
Got it?
知道了？
So why is their payout rate often low?
那么，为什么它们的赔付率通常很低呢？
He often completely is
他经常完全是
That's the reason described by the leader of the trauma team
这是创伤小组组长给出的理由。
It's just the tone in his voice
只是他说话的语气而已。
If this patient is described as
如果这位患者被描述为
It's all his fucking
这一切都是他他妈的
he asked for it
他要求的
there's no reasonable justification
没有合理的理由
No need to reimburse him
无需偿还他。
American doctors' depiction
美国医生的描述
the description of the American trauma team
美国创伤团队的描述
Often, it also determines whether the trauma company will compensate or not.
通常情况下，这也决定了创伤保险公司是否会进行赔偿。
Why doesn't the trauma company pay?
为什么创伤公司不赔付？
because in the doctor's description
因为在医生的描述中
The patient brought all of this upon themselves
这一切都是病人咎由自取。
He deserves it
他当之无愧。
he deserves to die
他罪该万死
Why do you eat foods high in oil, salt, and sugar?
你为什么喜欢吃高油、高盐、高糖的食物？
Why don't you take your leisure time to exercise
为什么不利用空闲时间锻炼一下呢？
As for you saying you work over ten hours a day
至于你说你每天工作超过十个小时，
Well I don't know about that
我对此并不了解。
As the leader of the trauma team
作为创伤团队的负责人
I might only see two or three patients a day.
我一天可能只能看两到三个病人。
He may not even perform one surgery a month
他可能一个月都不做一台手术。
That's just how it is
事情就是这样。
In his eyes
在他的眼中
He is not human
他并非人类
it's his patient
那是他的病人
not human
非人类
His patients are animals
他的病人是动物。
inferior creatures
低等生物
Someone said two or three, right?
有人说两三个，对吧？
The vast majority of American doctors probably only see two or three patients a day.
绝大多数美国医生可能一天只看两到三个病人。
America's medical... America's trauma teams live in absolute comfort.
美国的医疗……美国的创伤救护团队生活得非常舒适。
Ah, the leader of the trauma team is absolutely, absolutely living in the lap of luxury.
啊，创伤小组组长真是过着无比奢华的生活。
They live in villas
他们住在别墅里。
driving luxury cars, right
开豪华车，对吧？
want for nothing
什么都不缺
lacking nothing in food, drink, and entertainment
食物、饮料和娱乐一应俱全
You expect this kind of person to take a year off or not
你觉得这种人会休息一年吗？
people who get half a year off for their annual vacation
那些每年有半年假期的人
only work half a year with the other half on vacation
一年只工作半年，剩下的半年都在休假。
You expect him after his vacation
你期待他度假后回来。
Can they really provide good medical care for the poor?
他们真的能为穷人提供良好的医疗服务吗？
Got it
知道了
just a few patients
只有少数几位病人
Someone said, can't more doctors be assigned?
有人说，能不能多派些医生？
No
不
The doctor won't see them saying
医生不会看到他们这么说。
affect his mood
影响他的情绪
affect his treatment quality
影响他的治疗质量
The trauma team shouldn't be under such heavy workload
创伤团队不应该承受如此繁重的工作量。
As for you mentioning someone being sick and only receiving 30 yuan
至于你提到的有人生病却只领到 30 元钱的事。
Year after year without seeing
年复一年，不见
can't see a doctor
看不了医生
They just don't care
他们根本不在乎
They don't care either, hmm
他们也不在乎，嗯。
Ahh thank you Brother Arthur Burpot for the tip
啊，谢谢亚瑟·伯波特兄弟的提示
Let me take a look
让我看看
Well, Old Wei, if that's the case
老魏，如果真是那样的话……
Then American insurance companies really need to throw a Mario party
那么美国保险公司真的需要举办一场马里奥派对了。
party
派对
can't just have Luigi on the field
不能只让路易吉上场。
Every single one of them should take turns confronting the company's CEO, you know?
他们每个人都应该轮流与公司 CEO 对质，你知道吗？
That's true
这是真的
The U.S. should have done this long ago
美国早就应该这么做了。
The medical skills of these doctors,
这些医生的医术，
The medical skills of the trauma team leader are definitely inferior to those in China.
创伤小组组长的医疗技能明显不如中国同行。
Don't you worry
别担心
They see far too few patients
他们接诊的病人太少了。
Ah
啊
Let me put it this way
让我这样说吧
In the U.S., doctors and patients are completely two different classes
在美国，医生和病人是完全不同的两个阶层。
At the very least, they're of a different class from the majority of patients.
至少，他们与大多数患者属于不同的类别。
are worlds apart
相距甚远
All the leaders of the trauma teams are wealthy individuals
所有创伤小组的领导者都是富有的人。
are all upper class
他们都是上层阶级
You poor peasant
你这可怜的农民
you redneck
你这个乡巴佬
want proper medical treatment
想要得到适当的医疗护理
absolutely impossible
绝对不可能
you not only have to endure the physical pain
你不仅要忍受身体上的痛苦
You also have to endure the doctor's disdain
你还得忍受医生的轻蔑。
I have a definite feeling
我有一种很明确的感觉。
This feeling is extremely intense
这种感觉极其强烈。
It's just that
只是……
How intense can this get
这能有多激烈？
This doctor was the first to see me
这位医生是第一个给我看病的医生。
Because I was the first one to go
因为我是第一个去的
What was that day for?
那天是做什么的？
That day was for kidney stones.
那天是去做肾结石检查的。
Yeah, damn it, I drank water in the U.S.
是啊，真倒霉，我在美国喝了水。
drank so much that I fucking got kidney stones, damn it
喝了太多酒，结果得了肾结石，真他妈的！
found the trauma team leader
找到了创伤小组组长
Ah, he was so kind to me
啊，他对我真好。
That's just so great ah
真是太棒了啊
The demeanor is very elegant, isn't it?
他的举止非常优雅，不是吗？
no problem
没问题
Then the conversation turned to my studies.
然后话题转到了我的学业上。
He could even give me some advice on my studies, you know.
他甚至可以给我一些学习上的建议。
The doctor took a look and
医生看了一眼，
What do you study?
你学什么？
I said I'm an international student studying biochemistry
我说我是一名学习生物化学的国际学生。
The family member said, 'Oh my!'
这位家庭成员说：“我的天哪！”
A promising young talent, huh?
很有前途的年轻人才啊！
You're studying so well, aren't you?
你学习很努力，对吧？
Where do you live, huh?
你住在哪儿？
What courses are there and who is your professor?
有哪些课程？你的教授是谁？
Hey, just be pleasant and kind.
嘿，态度友善点就好。
I'm doing quite well
我一切都很好。
I'm quite happy
我非常高兴
As soon as I came out
我一出来
There's another one waiting outside
外面还有另一个在等着呢。
It's just too obvious
这太明显了
He only had two patients that day
那天他只有两个病人。
It's just me and one other person
只有我和另一个人
What kind of person is the other one?
另一个人是什么样的人？
was an old, worn-out welder
是一台老旧破损的焊机
Ah, that old worn-out welder, right?
啊，是那台老旧的焊机，对吧？
that drank too much soda
喝了太多汽水
diabetes
糖尿病
Ah, you could say they treat people differently based on their status
啊，可以说他们根据人们的地位区别对待他们。
you could say it's snobbish or whatever
你可以说这是势利眼之类的。
his attitude toward this old man
他对这位老人的态度
is completely different from the attitude towards Me
这与对我的态度截然不同。
That girl doesn't speak English well either
那个女孩英语也说得不好。
was interrogated by the doctor like a worthless grandson
被医生像审问没用的孙子一样审问
just
只是
the huge difference in the price of insurance purchased by both parties
双方购买的保险价格存在巨大差异
as well as the different social classes of patients
以及不同社会阶层的患者
which leads to the attitude when the trauma team receives the patient
这就导致了创伤团队接收病人时的态度。
Let's not even mention the attitude yet, whether this guy's illness can be cured or not
我们暂且不谈他的态度，也不管这人的病能不能治好。
the psychological harm he caused
他造成的心理伤害
I've been working all day
我今天工作了一整天。
Working over ten hours a day, right?
每天工作超过十个小时，对吧？
dead tired
累死了
I need to replenish a large amount of sugar
我需要补充大量的糖
I just like to drink some carbonated drinks
我只是喜欢喝碳酸饮料。
I work more than ten hours a day
我每天工作超过十个小时。
Then you tell me to quit drinking soda
然后你却让我戒掉汽水
and attribute it to my lack of exercise
并归咎于我缺乏运动。
Fitness
健康
being bad to yourself
对自己不好
So I could only opt for the most basic treatment
所以我只能选择最基本的治疗方案。
Because I don't deserve any other treatment options
因为我不配拥有其他治疗选择。
I'm just like you, you think everything is my own fault
我跟你一样，觉得一切都是我的错。
Then how can we play
那我们该怎么玩呢？
plus the medical public
以及医疗公众
Plus that insurance company, right?
再加上那家保险公司，对吧？
Oh dear
哦亲爱的
Your insurance is so cheap, right?
你的保险很便宜，对吧？
Then we can only go with conservative treatment.
那么我们就只能采取保守治疗了。
You can only use the most basic treatment plan, right?
你只能采用最基本的治疗方案，对吗？
Other treatment options are not covered by insurance.
其他治疗方案不在保险范围内。
This is
这是
This kind of presumptuous class discrimination by Americans
美国人这种自以为是的阶级歧视。
is terrifying
太可怕了
extremely terrifying
极其恐怖
The insurance companies are also inhumane
保险公司也毫无人性。
The entire treatment process was also quite unpleasant.
整个治疗过程也相当不愉快。
And what's even more terrifying is
更可怕的是……
Even if the health insurance company prescribes a treatment plan for you
即使医疗保险公司为你制定了治疗方案
They might still refuse to reimburse you in the end
他们最终可能还是会拒绝赔偿你。
As I mentioned before, he said, 'Oh no.'
正如我之前提到的，他说：“哦，不。”
You don't use a certain medical treatment
你不使用某种医疗手段
I won't reimburse
我不会报销。
Let me tell you
让我告诉你
sometimes it's still not covered even after you've used it
有时即使你已经使用过，它仍然不在承保范围内。
it's like that CEO of United Healthcare
就像联合健康保险公司的那位首席执行官一样
Why was he executed
他为何被处决
Why was he shot dead by Luigi with two gunshots?
他为什么会被路易吉连开两枪打死？
It's simple
很简单
Damn it
该死的
Your damn insurance company refuses to cover anything
你那该死的保险公司什么都不肯赔付。
This isn't covered either
这也不在涵盖范围内。
That won't be covered either, right?
那也不在承保范围内，对吧？
No reimbursement for the past
过去未予赔偿
Fuck, no reimbursement in the future either
操，以后也不会有赔偿了。
Then what the hell are we playing for
那我们到底在为什么而战
The rejection rate reaches 56%
拒绝率达到 56%。
Brothers, out of 100 people, 56 get rejected.
兄弟们，100 个人里，有 56 个被拒绝。
Then tell me which ordinary person can stand this?
那么请问，哪个普通人能忍受这种事？
I pay you every month
我每个月都付你钱
still have to be at your mercy
仍然要听命于你
I can't even decide my own medical treatment plan
我甚至无法决定自己的治疗方案。
not only can't decide
不仅无法决定
even after I finish seeing the doctor
即使我看完医生之后
You most likely won't reimburse me either
你很可能也不会赔偿我。
not to mention that ordinary people can't handle it, even young masters
更何况普通人根本应付不了，就连少爷们也一样。
He can't handle it either
他也处理不了。
Not even the young masters from wealthy families can handle it
就连富家少爷们也应付不了。
Some say it's not that few
有人说，其实没那么多。
The number of rejections is like this
拒绝次数大致如下
the number of people rejected for coverage
被拒保的人数
The comprehensive data shows a 56% rejection rate
综合数据显示，拒收率为 56%。
but for rare and complex diseases
但对于罕见病和复杂疾病而言，情况则有所不同。
serious illnesses
重病
and some cancer-related items
以及一些与癌症相关的物品
His probability of being denied coverage actually far exceeds 56%.
他被拒保的概率实际上远远超过 56%。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思？
It's just an average across all diseases
这只是所有疾病的平均值
It has a 56% rejection rate
它的拒绝率为 56%。
for major and difficult-to-treat diseases
对于重大且难以治疗的疾病
The rejection rate actually far exceeds 56%
实际拒绝率远高于 56%。
as long as your illness is slightly more serious
只要你的病情稍微严重一些。
you can just wait for rejection
你只能等着被拒绝了。
Well, some people say I have money
有人说我有钱。
I'm afraid of dying
我害怕死亡
I just bought the best health insurance
我刚买了一份最好的健康保险。
What would happen then?
那接下来会发生什么？
Hey, never seen a black guy before, right?
嘿，你以前没见过黑人吧？
Hey, been hospitalized twice
嘿，我住院过两次
over 200,000 in total
总计超过 20 万
this medical bill of over 200,000 dollars
这张医疗账单超过 20 万美元
560,000
｛1001｝
Hmph hmph hmph
哼哼哼
Is that the best medical insurance?
这是最好的医疗保险吗？
Ah, you got into trouble
啊，你惹上麻烦了。
We'll provide you with the best medical care at the finest hospital
我们将为您提供最好的医院和最优质的医疗服务。
done
完毕
You're out now
你现在可以出局了。
Owning over 200,000 yuan, right?
拥有超过 20 万元人民币，对吧？
Oh, not the Trauma Team, right?
哦，不是创伤小组吧？
Ah, the trauma team fee is over 200,000
啊，创伤小组的费用超过 20 万。
Did they manage to save him?
他们救了他吗？
That's also the price
这也是价格。
for the Trauma Team platinum membership ah
创伤团队白金会员资格啊
Insure him twice for over 200,000
给他投保两次，总保额超过 20 万。
around 260,000
约 26 万
That means you not only have to spend so much money out of your own pocket
这意味着你不仅要自掏腰包花很多钱。
your premium will also increase
您的保费也会增加。
the premium you have to pay every month
你每月必须缴纳的保费
He won't allow him
他不会允许他这么做。
he's increasing on top of what was already expensive for you before
他现在又增加了你原本就已经很贵的费用。
and it's going to increase by a huge amount again
而且它还会再次大幅增长。
The wool comes from the sheep's back.
羊毛取自绵羊的背部。
The so-called reimbursement he's talking about won't actually cover your costs
他所说的所谓报销实际上并不能弥补你的损失。
You just go ahead and enjoy the price hikes then.
那就好好享受物价上涨吧。
Someone asked how much Black Bro is still short
有人问黑兄弟还差多少钱。
Brother Hei is still far from it
黑哥离那一步还很远。
And don't forget, Black Guy
别忘了，黑人
How can he afford such high medical costs
他怎么负担得起这么高的医疗费用？
Don't forget that the black dude sells mushrooms
别忘了那个黑人是卖蘑菇的。
He sells LSD.
他贩卖迷幻药。
How could ordinary people have his financial strength?
普通人怎么可能有他那样的经济实力？
That would lead to two outcomes
这将导致两种结果
which makes it even worse
这让情况变得更糟。
Your hospital trauma team charges so much
你们医院的创伤团队收费太高了。
saved my life
救了我的命
I still have to pay such a huge amount of money
我仍然要支付一大笔钱。
After paying a huge sum of money
支付了一大笔钱之后
you're still fucking raising my premium
你他妈的还在涨我的保费。
Then guess what situation he would grow the mushrooms to
那么猜猜他会在什么情况下种植蘑菇？
It must be raised to the limit
必须将其提高到极限
Or expanding the foundation of their business
或者扩大其业务基础
Then guess what the social order would be like
那么你猜猜社会秩序会是什么样子？
extremely chaotic
极其混乱
Thank you, Brother J, for the reward
感谢 J 兄弟的奖励
there's a question
有个问题
In my eyes
在我眼中
American family doctors and community health center doctors who are also physicians
美国家庭医生和社区卫生中心医生（同时也是内科医生）
community doctors and other primary healthcare workers
社区医生和其他基层医疗保健工作者
their treatment compared to
他们受到的待遇与……相比
Are doctors in big city hospitals much worse?
大城市医院的医生水平就差很多吗？
but they are also wealthy
但他们也很富有。
Previously saw that anecdote about the American ophthalmologist
之前看过关于那位美国眼科医生的轶事
feel like their family doctors are under a lot of pressure
他们感觉自己的家庭医生压力很大。
almost greater than the emergency doctors here
几乎比这里的急诊医生还要多。
Right
正确的
Because you can only see the family doctor.
因为你只能去看家庭医生。
If you didn't graduate from a prestigious university
如果你没有从名牌大学毕业
no letter of recommendation
没有推荐信
you're basically stuck at the grassroots level for life
你基本上一辈子都只能待在基层。
Of course, they earn quite a bit, right?
当然，他们收入相当可观，对吧？
So you're saying they have grievances, right?
所以你的意思是他们心怀不满，对吗？
But they earn quite a bit
但他们收入相当可观。
just so-so
一般般
even those so-called family doctors
甚至那些所谓的家庭医生
farm doctor
农场医生
community doctor
社区医生
They can still earn two or three hundred thousand, right?
他们仍然可以赚到二三十万，对吧？
I wouldn't dare say several million
我不敢说有几百万。
Two or three hundred thousand dollars is still possible, okay
二三十万美元还是有可能的，好的。
That doesn't mean more people will come for treatment, right? Exactly.
但这并不意味着会有更多人来接受治疗，对吧？正是如此。
This is a vicious cycle
这是一个恶性循环。
Bro, you just realized that?
兄弟，你现在才意识到？
This is an extremely terrifying vicious cycle
这是一个极其可怕的恶性循环。
Really
真的
And you know what, I'd like to ask
你知道吗，我想问……
If he is faced with such potentially high-net-worth users
如果他面对的是这类潜在的高净值用户
What would he do
他会怎么做？
Brother Hei is a high-net-worth individual
黑哥是一位高净值人士。
They'll also charge you a huge medical bill
他们还会向你收取巨额医疗费用。
make you pay
让你付出代价
You can afford it, right?
你买得起吧？
Can you afford it, right?
We roughly know what your income bracket is
我们大致了解您的收入水平。
They have actuaries
他们有精算师
I've calculated roughly how much you earn in a year, right?
我已经大致估算出你一年的收入是多少，对吧？
We know you can earn that money.
我们知道你能挣到那笔钱。
Then he wields that big machete to slash people, hmm
然后他就挥舞着那把大砍刀砍人，嗯。
Very accurate, extremely precise
非常准确，极其精确
Please be very careful
请务必小心
Please do not underestimate them, okay?
请不要低估他们，好吗？
these financial conglomerates in Europe and America
欧洲和美国的这些金融集团
the actuaries of these medical consortiums and insurance consortiums uh
这些医疗联盟和保险联盟的精算师们
They are extremely capable
他们能力极强。
resourceful
足智多谋
Please do believe in their expertise
请相信他们的专业能力。
Ah, just one more thing
啊，还有一件事。
Isn't this how Europe and America end up massively inflating the hidden costs of people's livelihoods and public safety?
难道这不是欧洲和美国大幅推高民众生活和公共安全隐性成本的原因吗？
hidden costs skyrocket
隐性成本飙升
Right
正确的
Why are Americans particularly afraid of getting injured
为什么美国人特别害怕受伤
why is a small community with $300 per month
为什么一个每月只有 300 美元的小社区会这样
Not everyone dares to live there
并非人人都敢住在那里。
It's prone to accidents
它容易发生事故
Once something happens, he needs to see a doctor
一旦发生什么事，他就需要去看医生。
Once you seek medical treatment, you're likely to be denied coverage.
一旦你寻求医疗救治，你的保险很可能会被拒绝。
Once he gets denied insurance, he has to take painkillers.
一旦他的保险被拒，他就只能服用止痛药。
Also, why do Americans misuse painkillers
另外，为什么美国人会滥用止痛药？
For example, if you're trying to save money and rent a place for $300
例如，如果你想省钱，租一个每月 300 美元的房子
rented an apartment in a crappy gang neighborhood
在治安很差、帮派横行的街区租了一套公寓
you rent it cheaply
你可以低价租到它
Then one day you got your leg blown open by a grenade, huh
然后有一天，你的腿被手榴弹炸开了，是吗？
suffered a penetrating wound
遭受穿透性伤口
went to the hospital for surgery and ended up
去医院做手术，结果
ended up owing tens of thousands of dollars in loans
最终欠下了数万美元的贷款。
The health insurance premium has gone up again.
健康保险费又涨了。
The doctor sees your situation
医生了解你的情况。
He won't prescribe much medication for you either.
他也不会给你开太多药。
Didn't you hurt your leg?
你的腿没受伤吗？
Aren't you in pain?
你不觉得疼吗？
To make you keep taking medicine from me
为了让你继续服用我的药
I want to make long-term money off you
我想从你身上赚取长期的利益。
I'll just prescribe you painkillers
我给你开点止痛药吧。
What if I say I don't want to take it?
如果我说我不想接受呢？
He said if you don't take it
他说，如果你不接受它
There's nothing else either
没有别的了。
If you don't take it, there's no alternative
如果你不接受，就没有其他办法了。
take it or leave it
接受或拒绝
Then can you prescribe me something
那么你能给我开点药吗？
Just cure this disease for me directly
请直接治好我的这种病
No
不
The medical company doesn't cover it.
医疗保险公司不予承保。
If you want to take it, you have to pay the full amount yourself.
如果你想买，就得自己支付全款。
You're saying I owe you a huge medical bill, right?
你是说我欠你一大笔医疗费，对吧？
even if it's reimbursed
即使可以报销
Then my insurance premium also increased
然后我的保险费也上涨了。
Now you're making me pay full price for medication
现在你们要我全价买药。
medicine
药品
Isn't this just killing me?
这简直要了我的命！
The doctor said this is for your own good
医生说这是为了你好。
Be good, okay?
要乖哦？
Take painkillers
服用止痛药
Painkillers are cheap
止痛药很便宜
You take some painkillers first
你先服用一些止痛药。
First, be able to work
首先，要有工作能力。
earn the money
挣钱
after paying off the loan
还清贷款后
Many Americans are not unaware of the issues with painkillers.
许多美国人并非不了解止痛药的问题。
He has no choice
他别无选择
He had no choice, the doctors and uh
他别无选择，医生们也……
The trauma team and insurance company don't give him a choice
创伤小组和保险公司不给他选择的余地。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思？
He had no choice
他别无选择
How could he choose
他怎么会选择
He had no choice
他别无选择
He could only take painkillers first
他只能先服用止痛药。
earn the money first
先挣钱
pay back the money first to avoid the fraud cycle
先还钱，避免陷入诈骗循环。
If you don't want to get caught in this cycle
如果你不想陷入这种循环的话。
you have to pay a high price to rent a good house
租一套好房子需要付出高昂的代价。
so some of these emigrants
所以，这些移民中的一些人
and some
还有一些
domestic straight men
国内直男
The problem with him is
他的问题在于
Exactly.
确切地。
I see even in this neighborhood in Los Angeles
即使在洛杉矶的这个社区，我也看到了这一点。
There are also damn houses that cost a few hundred dollars a month
还有一些房子，每月租金只要几百美元。
Why doesn't anyone live there, right?
对吧，为什么那里没人住呢？
Why can't I live there?
为什么我不能住在那里？
I would live there if it were me, right?
如果是我，我会住在那儿，对吧？
He doesn't consider the safety environment at all
他根本不考虑安全环境。
He has no idea what it's like to get injured in that kind of neighborhood
他根本不知道在那种社区受伤是什么滋味。
what kind of outcome it would be
会是什么样的结果呢？
That's a hellish outcome.
那真是个糟糕的结果。
It's practically equivalent to a death sentence.
这实际上等同于死刑。
Yeah, right
是啊，没错
someone said
有人说
Why must you live in a house that costs two to three thousand dollars a month
你为什么一定要住在每月花费两三千美元的房子里呢？
Can't you live in a house that costs two or three hundred dollars a month?
你难道不能住一套每月租金两三百美元的房子吗？
Sorry
对不起
That means it's not habitable
这意味着它不适宜居住。
Hey Old A, let me ask you something
嘿，老 A，我问你个问题
I've seen a lot of
我见过很多
so uh some people in China worship foreign medical systems
所以，呃，中国有些人崇拜外国医疗体系。
go abroad for medical treatment
出国就医
Well, if they go to those relatively high-end ones abroad,
嗯，如果他们去国外那些相对高端的学校的话，
Because they usually go to those so-called
因为他们通常会去那些所谓的
higher-end medical institutions
高端医疗机构
Would these medical institutions also specifically target this group of clients
这些医疗机构是否也会专门针对这部分客户群体？
customized for this group with purchasing power
专为这个具有购买力的群体量身定制
It must be a tailor-made slashing plan
这一定是量身定制的削减计划
What are you thinking about
你在想什么？
Let me tell you, it's exactly the same medicine
我告诉你，这药跟原来的药一模一样。
The same medication is sold at different prices to two different groups of people.
同一种药物以不同的价格出售给两类不同的人群。
The poor get a lower price
穷人能买到更便宜的东西
The price is a bit higher for the wealthy
对于富裕人来说，价格会略高一些。
Domestically, no matter what
在国内，无论如何
can definitely cure you
绝对可以治好你
What if someone says poor people don't have insurance?
如果有人说穷人没有保险呢？
He's too poor to afford insurance.
他太穷了，买不起保险。
Then go to the church and pray
然后去教堂祈祷
pray for God's grace, right
祈求神的恩典，对吧？
Hope they pull through
希望他们能挺过去
Then the church just arranges a bed for them
然后教会就给他们安排了一张床。
just put them in the back and wait for death
把它们放在后面，等着死亡吧
Do you remember me talking about the 'True Stories of American Workers' Deaths' series
你还记得我谈到的“美国工人死亡真实故事”系列吗？
that episode
那一集
How did that old Mo die in the church?
老莫是怎么死在教堂里的？
no medical care
未接受医疗护理
left there to die, huh
被遗弃在那里等死，是吗？
Would these kinds of churches take advantage of such situations
这类教会是否会利用这种情况
when these people are desperate
当这些人绝望的时候
is through
是通过
Because I've seen some American films
因为我看过一些美国电影
There are also such films that would say
也有一些电影会说
They'll give you some placebo
他们会给你一些安慰剂。
but the placebo was also mixed with something
但是安慰剂里也混入了其他东西。
is to make you feel a little better for a while
是为了让你暂时感觉好一些。
don't howl so miserably
别那么悲惨地嚎叫
affecting the visitors to Dubai
影响到访迪拜的游客
You wish to be treated well
你希望受到善待。
That doesn't exist
那并不存在。
Then tell them to go directly to churches or other physical places to sell for money
然后告诉他们直接去教堂或其他实体场所出售商品赚钱。
Wouldn't that make a fortune
那岂不是能发大财？
Guess why I do hospice care
猜猜我为什么从事临终关怀工作
these homeless people
这些无家可归的人
these low-income undocumented immigrants
这些低收入的无证移民
their bodies are often sold off
他们的身体经常被卖掉。
because their families simply have no place to bury them
因为他们的家人根本没有地方埋葬他们。
cannot afford burial
负担不起丧葬费用
Let me tell you all
让我来告诉你们一切
those who died from the infectious disease COVID-19
那些死于新冠肺炎的人
their bodies cannot be buried directly
他们的遗体不能直接埋葬。
must undergo special treatment
必须接受特殊待遇
This special treatment is very expensive.
这种特殊治疗非常昂贵。
The vast majority of lower-class families cannot afford this expense.
绝大多数低收入家庭都负担不起这笔开支。
is to make some money by donating the body
捐献遗体是为了赚钱。
you can still earn some money to help with household expenses
你仍然可以赚些钱来帮助支付家庭开支。
As for how their father's corpse is violated or desecrated
至于他们父亲的遗体是如何被亵渎或玷污的
there's nothing that can be done
无能为力。
This is why sometimes people look at America and it's the opposite
这就是为什么有时人们看待美国，会发现情况恰恰相反。
Why doesn't he trust American medicine?
他为什么不信任美国医学？
not to be trusted
不可信赖
don't trust vaccines
不要相信疫苗
don't trust medicine
不要相信药物
that kind of stuff that doesn't trust any medical care provided by the US
那种人不信任美国提供的任何医疗服务。
Why do they have PTSD
他们为什么会患上创伤后应激障碍？
Look at the things I’ve talked about today
看看我今天都谈到了些什么
I've already
我已经
Actually, I consider myself to be a rather tender-hearted person.
事实上，我认为自己是一个心地比较重的人。
I've cried many times
我哭过很多次
I've really cried many times
我真的哭过很多次
These tears have long since dried up
这些眼泪早已干涸。
Do you understand?
你明白吗？
Sometimes they conduct medical experiments on their own people, no
有时他们会在自己的人民身上进行医学实验，没有。
That's no rumor
那不是谣言
That's true
这是真的
There were cases as early as the last century.
早在上个世纪就出现过这种情况。
This is
这是
This is not the first time, huh
这已经不是第一次了，是吧？
The probability of you getting painkillers in the American healthcare system
你在美国医疗保健系统中获得止痛药的概率
is far greater than your chances of getting antibiotics like penicillin
比你获得青霉素等抗生素的几率要大得多
It's completely normal for Americans not to believe it.
美国人不相信这一点完全正常。
He believes in ghosts, huh
他相信有鬼啊。
Hey
嘿
including one of the most famous conspiracy theories
其中包括最著名的阴谋论之一
that is, so many planes flying over the North American continent
也就是说，有如此多的飞机飞越北美大陆。
the smoke sprayed from those planes
那些飞机喷出的烟雾
are all chemical agents meant to harm the general public or something
这些都是旨在危害公众的化学制剂吗？
Why do you say that
你为什么这么说？
because your CIA did the same thing back in Vietnam
因为你们的中央情报局在越南也干过同样的事。
the same thing
同一件事
What they did was really fucked up.
他们做的事真是太糟糕了。
right
正确的
Some people in the danmu (bullet comment) also said they don't believe it
弹幕评论区也有人表示不相信。
ironically survive and reinforce stereotypes
具有讽刺意味的是，这种现象反而会加剧刻板印象。
like those famous ones you see
就像你看到的那些名人一样
It's like those crazy lunatics you see in all sorts of literary works
就像你在各种文学作品中看到的那些疯子一样
And then
进而
Actually, that madman in the end is
实际上，最后那个疯子是
You could say he is a wise old man who has been through a lot.
可以说他是一位饱经风霜的睿智老人。
or a wind
或者一阵风
or a normal person
或者普通人
Actually a normal person
实际上，一个普通人
Why is it that the Seven Greats themselves forced it out?
为什么七大伟人要亲自把它驱逐出去？
I don't know what to say
我不知道该说什么
And also, there's the way Americans treat vaccination
此外，还有美国人对待疫苗接种的方式。
they just don't get vaccinated either
他们根本不接种疫苗。
It's also because Americans have long used Americans as test subjects, huh
也是因为美国人长期以来一直把美国人当作试验对象，是吧？
Ha, they say it's a vaccine
哈哈，他们说那是疫苗。
actually injected some unknown bullshit stuff
实际上注入了一些不明的垃圾东西
into the body
进入体内
Hehehe
呵呵呵
And what's even more terrifying is
更可怕的是……
it's just that some of their stuff is designed from the very beginning
只是他们的一些产品从一开始就是设计好的。
tracking them from different stages of life
追踪他们人生的不同阶段
They don't administer it to adults
他们不给成年人使用这种药物。
not even given to children
甚至都没给孩子
It's given to infants
它是给婴儿用的
They make infants carry it for their entire lives
他们让婴儿终生携​​带它
Do you know how beastly he is?
你知道他有多残暴吗？
injecting babies
给婴儿注射
Brothers, they weren't even children.
他们是兄弟，甚至都不是孩子。
and then observe them for their entire lives
然后观察他们的一生
Ah, injecting Black people with syphilis
啊，给黑人注射梅毒
That's still considered good
那仍然被认为是好的
That's right, isn't it?
没错，不是吗？
the good deeds of Western society
西方社会的善行
Not to mention their way of thinking
更别提他们的思维方式了。
some of them have been adopted by certain Seres individuals
其中一些已被某些塞雷斯人收养。
people who didn't study biology properly have come to like it
那些没有认真学过生物学的人也开始喜欢它了。
You know what
你知道吗
Because I really in real life
因为在现实生活中我真的
Someone told me
有人告诉我
Someone said this to me
有人跟我说过这句话
that vaccine is just blah blah blah
那种疫苗简直就是……
I was totally stunned
我当时完全惊呆了。
I was like holy shit
我当时就想：卧槽
They are saving your life
它们正在拯救你的生命
give you injections for free
免费给你注射
you even bite the hand that feeds you
你甚至恩将仇报。
That's the Chinese way of thinking
这就是中国人的思维方式。
There's no way to prevent the spread
目前没有办法阻止传播。
How about the airplane
飞机怎么样？
Oh
哦
So you Americans are really inhumane
所以你们美国人真是毫无人性。
This is really true
这确实是真的
Listen to me talk about the historical burden on the United States
请听我谈谈美国的历史负担。
Don’t look at him
别看他
Don't underestimate this country just because its history is short
不要因为这个国家历史短就低估它。
It has a heavy historical baggage.
它背负着沉重的历史包袱。
done all sorts of evil deeds
做了各种各样的恶事
Sigh, thanks for the big tip from this dude, damn it
唉，真感谢这哥们儿给的这条重要线索，该死的。
Every time I hear the boss talk about
每次我听到老板谈论……
The healthcare in the U.S. is quite disheartening
美国的医疗保健状况令人相当失望。
Just came to realize
突然意识到
Could it be the stuff they took in back then
会不会是他们当时带进去的那些东西？
overly marinated and flavorful, huh
腌制过度，味道太浓郁了，是吧？
Yeah, sigh
唉，唉。
Fort Detrick in the U.S. simply took over all the stuff from Unit 731.
美国德特里克堡直接接管了 731 部队的所有物资。
The United States, including the Chinese habit of drinking hot water,
美国，包括中国人喝热水的习惯，
This habit only emerged after the Korean War
这种习惯是在朝鲜战争之后才出现的。
Why during the Korean War
为什么是在朝鲜战争期间
The United States employed recruited personnel from Unit 731
美国从第 731 部队招募人员。
how do we prevent
我们如何预防
drinking hot water
喝热水
drink boiled water
喝开水
The Chinese habit of drinking hot water originated from here.
中国人喝热水的习惯起源于此。
This is just a habit that has only existed for a few decades.
这只是近几十年才出现的一种习惯。
calling on the whole nation to drink hot water
呼吁全国人民喝热水
take hot showers
洗个热水澡
Let me tell you guys
让我告诉你们这些家伙
Do you think settling accounts with Japan is enough?
你认为与日本清算旧账就足够了吗？
No way
决不
We will eventually settle accounts with the United States.
我们最终会与美国清算账目。
Not settling accounts with the U.S. is unacceptable
不与美国结算账目是不可接受的。
You know what?
你知道吗？
mainly in the entire Korean Peninsula
主要分布在整个朝鲜半岛
the northeastern and even northern China regions
中国东北乃至中国北部地区
they were all deployed
他们全部被部署了
Some say it was only distributed in the Northeast
有人说它只在东北地区发行。
No.
不。
He delivers in many places.
他在很多地方都有演出。
Why why back then was the call for the whole nation to drink hot water
为什么当时号召全国人民喝热水？
really
真的
Do you really think the Korean War was the peak?
你真的认为朝鲜战争是历史的巅峰吗？
No
不
The Vietnam War was the peak.
越南战争是巅峰时期。
Why is Vietnam developing so slowly
为什么越南发展如此缓慢？
has a lot to do with their intelligence
这与他们的智力有很大关系。
A significant portion of Vietnamese children have intellectual disabilities
越南儿童中有相当一部分患有智力障碍。
Why not
为什么不呢？
Then take a look at what the U.S. military dropped in Vietnam
然后看看美军在越南投放了什么。
I do sympathize with the Vietnamese people on this point.
在这一点上，我非常同情越南人民。
Do you know what it's like for an entire village
你知道整个村庄的感受吗？
what it's like for all the women to have stillbirths
所有经历过死产的女性都经历了怎样的感受
scenario
设想
This is entire villages of women
这是整个妇女村庄。
could not give birth
无法分娩
normal babies are born as stillbirths
正常婴儿出生时是死胎
Ah, there are also many cases of intellectual impairment
啊，智力障碍的案例也很多。
Sometimes I genuinely feel sorry for the Vietnamese people
有时我真的会同情越南人民。
not fake pity
不是虚假的怜悯
is truly pitiful
真是可怜
Just imagine
试想一下
a mother gave birth to a deformed baby, right
一位母亲生下了一个畸形婴儿，没错。
and it's not just her giving birth alone
而且不仅仅是她独自一人生产。
All the women in the village couldn't give birth to
村里所有的妇女都无法生育。
normal children, as if heaven has forsaken them
普通的孩子，仿佛上天抛弃了他们。
no one to turn to on earth
世上无人可求助
This is the situation, it's just that it didn't happen in China
情况就是这样，只不过这种事没有发生在中国。
otherwise that kind of deep-seated hatred
否则，那种根深蒂固的仇恨
Ah, got shot. Hmm, got shot.
啊，中枪了。嗯，中枪了。
suddenly shot dead, hmm
突然被枪杀，嗯？
Three days, huh
三天啊
We said
我们说
What are we talking about
我们在讨论什么？
after all once
毕竟曾经